<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Love Licton</title><link href="https://lovelicton.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://lovelicton.com/feeds/all-en.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://lovelicton.com/</id><updated>2018-11-04T20:00:00-08:00</updated><entry><title>Coffee is back in Licton Springs!</title><link href="https://lovelicton.com/pilrim_coffee_comes_to_oaktree.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-11-04T20:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2018-11-04T20:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>timothycrosley</name></author><id>tag:lovelicton.com,2018-11-04:/pilrim_coffee_comes_to_oaktree.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;We've just been given news we couldn't be happier to report:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pilgrim Coffee is coming to Oak Tree plaza!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/pilgrim/poster.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Poster" src="/images/pilgrim/poster.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Starting tomorrow Pilgrim Coffee will be operating at 10002 Aurora Ave N Monday - Wednesday 7-10 AM, and we've heard rumors that if demand is high enough they may expand their hours …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We've just been given news we couldn't be happier to report:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pilgrim Coffee is coming to Oak Tree plaza!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/pilgrim/poster.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Poster" src="/images/pilgrim/poster.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Starting tomorrow Pilgrim Coffee will be operating at 10002 Aurora Ave N Monday - Wednesday 7-10 AM, and we've heard rumors that if demand is high enough they may expand their hours next month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's been a little less than two months since &lt;a href="https://lovelicton.com/original_north_seattle_starbucks_closing.html"&gt;Starbucks left Licton Spring's urban village&lt;/a&gt;, leaving the area without any coffee options.
Tomorrow that all changes. While many would have been content with almost any Coffee Shop setting up at the location, we couldn't be more ecstatic that our favorite Coffee Truck
is setting up right in front of the old Starbucks. We've been a fan of Pilgrim Coffee for a while, as they've roasted some great coffee right here in the neighborhood:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/pilgrim/roasts.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Roasts" src="/images/pilgrim/roasts.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It also doesn't hurt that the opening happens at the perfect time for holiday-inspired drinks:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/pilgrim/holiday_drinks.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Holiday Drink Specials" src="/images/pilgrim/holiday_drinks.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We hope you will join us drinking some great local coffee!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="General"></category><category term="Retail"></category><category term="Coffee"></category><category term="Business Openings"></category></entry><entry><title>Leaves are Falling &amp; Autumn is Here: November Community Events</title><link href="https://lovelicton.com/november-events-2018.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-11-01T20:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-11-01T20:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>amandacrosley</name></author><id>tag:lovelicton.com,2018-11-01:/november-events-2018.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Correction (11/5/18): The ALUV meeting has been cancelled this month due to scheduling conflicts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We hope everyone had fun at the Licton Springs Park Halloween Walk yesterday! There were over 300 trick-or-treaters and lots of great costumes!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/events/2018/october/halloween_crowd.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Hundreds come out for Halloween event" src="/images/events/2018/october/halloween_crowd.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am certainly &lt;em&gt;thankful&lt;/em&gt; for all of the great upcoming community …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Correction (11/5/18): The ALUV meeting has been cancelled this month due to scheduling conflicts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We hope everyone had fun at the Licton Springs Park Halloween Walk yesterday! There were over 300 trick-or-treaters and lots of great costumes!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/events/2018/october/halloween_crowd.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Hundreds come out for Halloween event" src="/images/events/2018/october/halloween_crowd.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am certainly &lt;em&gt;thankful&lt;/em&gt; for all of the great upcoming community events happening this month. Check them out below!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;LoveLicton Sponsored Events:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Saturday, November 24th, @ 12PM-2PM, &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/341916543226078/"&gt;Board Games and Coffee&lt;/a&gt;, Neighborcare Health at Meridian 10521 Meridian Ave N&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/events/2018/november/board_games.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Board Game Event" src="/images/events/2018/november/board_games.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take a quick break from the holidays, meet your neighbors, and join us for free board games, party games, and snacks at Meridian Health room 110. All are welcome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wednesday, November 28th @ 6PM, &lt;a href="https://www.meetup.com/North-Seattle-Tech-Talks/events/255745950/"&gt;In Practice: Applying Secure Software Design Principles in Open Source&lt;/a&gt;, North Seattle College, Room CC1161&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/events/2018/november/in_practice.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="North Seattle Tech Talks In Practice" src="/images/events/2018/november/in_practice.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"In Practice" meetups provide an opportunity to contribute to Open Source Projects. For new contributors, there will be seasoned contributors and projects maintainers available during the Meetup to help direct you through the process. All contributions, from code to graphic design and documentation are welcome. If you've always wanted to get involved in Open Source or work on projects with other developers in the community this is a great way to start!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Social &amp;amp; Networking Events:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sunday, November 4th, @ 11AM-3PM, &lt;a href="https://www.northwestdanish.org/danish-holiday-bazaar/"&gt;Danish Holiday Bazaar&lt;/a&gt;, Northwest Danish Association 1833 N 105th St #101&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/events/2018/november/holiday_bazaar.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Holiday Bazaar" src="/images/events/2018/november/holiday_bazaar.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eat delicious smørrebrød (Danish open-faced sandwiches) and do your holiday shopping!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Bazaar offers unique gifts, homemade Danish Christmas crafts, Christmas items from Denmark, Danish Christmas cookies, cake, and much more. Unique Danish julekurve (Christmas baskets) are raffled off to lucky winners! Open to the public.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Saturday, November 10th, @ 9AM-5PM, &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1082305698605711/"&gt;Better Book Sale&lt;/a&gt;, North Seattle College 9600 College Way N.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/events/2018/november/books.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Book Sale" src="/images/events/2018/november/books.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don't miss Friends of The Seattle Public Library one-day "better" book sale! This sale features hundreds of "like-new," gift quality books of all genres starting at $3!
The sale will be held in the OLD Cafeteria on the 1st Floor of the College Center Building located in the SE corner of the North Seattle Campus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Friday, November 16, 2018, @ 6PM-9PM, &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/295273121196762/"&gt;International Night&lt;/a&gt;, North Seattle College, Room CC1456&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/events/2018/november/international_night.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="International Night" src="/images/events/2018/november/international_night.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;International Night is the biggest party of the year!
International Night promotes understanding of other cultures through food, music, dance and celebration!
Come for the free food, stay for the talent show!
Performers are from all over the world!
Free and open to everyone!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are you IN?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Community Engagement Events:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Monday, November 5th, @ 8PM, &lt;a href="http://www.seattle.gov/DPD/aboutus/news/events/DesignReview/Detail/default.aspx?id=7064"&gt;Northgate Early Design Guidance Meeting&lt;/a&gt;, Good Shepherd Center, 4649 Sunnyside Ave N, Room 202&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Design Review Early Design Guidance for a Major Phased Development for eleven buildings with, retail sales and service, office, sports and recreation and hotel. Parking for 1100 vehicles proposed. Some existing structures to be demolished.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wednesday, November 7th, @ 7PM, &lt;a href="http://seattlenpac.blogspot.com/2018/10/november-npac-meets-wednesday-november.html"&gt;Seattle North Precinct Advisory Council&lt;/a&gt;, Cascadia Elementary School 1700 N 90th St&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The North Precinct Advisory Council is a community organization devoted to promoting partnership between residents, schools, businesses, and the Seattle Police Department to effectively address public safety issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CANCELLED  due to scheduling conflicts &lt;span style="text-decoration: line-through;"&gt;Thursday, November 8th @ 7PM, &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/AuroraLicton"&gt;ALUV Monthly Meeting&lt;/a&gt;, Epic Life Church 10510 Stone Ave N&lt;span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration: line-through;"&gt;
    ALUV stands for Aurora Licton Urban Village and seeks to build a pedestrian-safe, visually vibrant, economically sound, livable, and welcoming urban village using sustainable-growth principles.
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Saturday, November 10th @ 10AM, &lt;a href="https://lictonsprings.org/work_party.pdf"&gt;Friends of Licton Springs Park Clean Up&lt;/a&gt;, Licton Springs Park&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Join FRIENDS OF LICTON SPRINGS for our monthly work parties&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tuesday, November 13th @ 6PM, &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/302070293727106/"&gt;Mineral Springs Park Community Meeting&lt;/a&gt;, Neighborcare Health at Meridian 10521 Meridian Ave N&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Discuss Mineral Springs Park events, work parties, and community engagement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wednesday, November 14th @ 6:30PM, &lt;a href="https://lictonsprings.org/"&gt;Licton Springs Community Council Meeting&lt;/a&gt;, Neighborcare Health at Meridian 10521 Meridian Ave N&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Join Licton Springs Community Council for our monthly meeting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To stay up to date on other activities coming up, check out LoveLicton's &lt;a href="https://lovelicton.com/pages/community-calendar.html"&gt;calendar&lt;/a&gt;.
Hope to see you at an upcoming event!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Did we miss something? Let us know in the comments below!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="General"></category><category term="Community Meeting"></category><category term="Event"></category><category term="Outdoors"></category><category term="Parks"></category><category term="Tech"></category></entry><entry><title>North Seattle Precinct set to expand Licton Springs footprint</title><link href="https://lovelicton.com/north-precinct-set-to-grow.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-10-29T23:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-10-29T23:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>timothycrosley</name></author><id>tag:lovelicton.com,2018-10-29:/north-precinct-set-to-grow.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Where College Way N and Meridian Ave N meet in Licton Springs there is a small police station. That station is responsible for serving all of North Seattle. From Ballard to UDistrict, Fremont to Haller Lake, all of them are served by the North Precinct. This easily makes it the …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Where College Way N and Meridian Ave N meet in Licton Springs there is a small police station. That station is responsible for serving all of North Seattle. From Ballard to UDistrict, Fremont to Haller Lake, all of them are served by the North Precinct. This easily makes it the station that serves both the largest land area and population.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src="https://www.google.com/maps/d/embed?mid=1pq76mrRNksF3pvM-Z0xgeFuBW-UuPdPn" width="640" height="480"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Naturally, this has led for many calls to split the precinct, or most recently, replace it with a new much larger location (on Aurora). However, thus far, there hasn't been political alignment to turn these calls into reality. The most recent of which was stopped by a counter campaign to &lt;a href="http://council.seattle.gov/2016/09/16/sawant-block-the-bunker-activists-to-celebrate-victory-on-north-precinct-call-to-use-funds-for-housing/"&gt;"Block the Bunker"&lt;/a&gt;, primarily driven from those who live in areas that aren't in the area served by the precinct they wish to block.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, if you walk by the precinct, you will be greeted by many land use signs. The North Precinct plans to increase its footprint at its current location.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="images/precinct/development.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="North Precinct Expansion" src="images/precinct/development.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where grass and greenery used to be, &lt;a href="https://www.seattle.gov/Documents/Departments/NorthPrecinctStation/NorthPrecinctFlyer.pdf"&gt;the precinct plans to pave additional parking and add portables&lt;/a&gt;.
The plan isn't meant to be a permanent solution, but the hope is it will enable the precinct to keep up with the next 5-7 years of growth.
And while there is concern by many over the loss of greenspace as &lt;a href="http://web6.seattle.gov/dpd/edms/"&gt;illustrated in the public comments&lt;/a&gt; (record # 3031508-LU), with no other agreed on options,
combined with an increasing call for greater public safety and police presence, it seems increasingly likely that we will see the start of an expanded precinct in Licton Springs come this time next year.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="General"></category><category term="Construction"></category><category term="Police"></category><category term="North Seattle"></category></entry><entry><title>North Seattle Prepares for Light Rail</title><link href="https://lovelicton.com/north-seattle-prepares-for-light-rail.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-10-20T02:30:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-10-20T02:30:00-07:00</updated><author><name>amandacrosley</name></author><id>tag:lovelicton.com,2018-10-20:/north-seattle-prepares-for-light-rail.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Earlier this month, residents of North Seattle gathered to share information, resources, and get connected at U District's Let's Go Transit Talk. The U District, Roosevelt, and Northgate Link light rail stations will arrive in 2021 which means these neighborhoods, as well as Licton Springs, will be better connected to …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Earlier this month, residents of North Seattle gathered to share information, resources, and get connected at U District's Let's Go Transit Talk. The U District, Roosevelt, and Northgate Link light rail stations will arrive in 2021 which means these neighborhoods, as well as Licton Springs, will be better connected to each other and Downtown Seattle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/light_rail/panel.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Panel" src="/images/light_rail/panel.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Panelists included:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Amy Gore, &lt;a href="https://www.seattle.gov/council/johnson"&gt; Seattle City Councilmember Rob Johnson's Office District 4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inga Manskopf,&lt;a href="http://www.ravennabryant.org/"&gt; Ravenna Bryant Community Association&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Laura Loe,&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/sharethecities"&gt; Share the Cities&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mark Crawford,&lt;a href="https://www.udistrictpartnership.org/"&gt; U District Partnership&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Joe Gruber,&lt;a href="http://www.udistrictfoodbank.org/"&gt; University District Food Bank&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jeffrey Young,&lt;a href="https://northseattle.edu/parking-transportation/orca-transit-pass"&gt; North Seattle College&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scott Cooper,&lt;a href="http://rooseveltseattle.org/"&gt; Roosevelt Neighborhood Association&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bill Bryant,&lt;a href="https://kingcounty.gov/depts/transportation/metro/contact-us.aspx"&gt; King County Metro Transit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ellen Blair,&lt;a href="https://www.soundtransit.org/contact-us"&gt; Sound Transit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ann Sutphin, &lt;a href="https://www.seattle.gov/transportation"&gt;Seattle Department of Transportation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of particular interest to those in the Licton Springs area, we heard from Jeffrey Young about the upcoming pedestrian bridge connecting Licton Springs to Northgate's light rail station with plans to focus on preserving the wetlands while achieving safety in the design:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/yEF4kf3CGmE?start=2730&amp;end=2880" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; encrypted-media" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, Jeffrey mentioned upcoming plans (in the next two years) for additional student housing at North Seattle College including a 300-bed residence hall:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/yEF4kf3CGmE?start=2880&amp;end=2957" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; encrypted-media" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find the full recording of the session here: &lt;a href="http://www.seattlechannel.org/misc-video?videoid=x98788"&gt;http://www.seattlechannel.org/misc-video?videoid=x98788&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As well as more information about U District, Let's Go Transit Talks here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://udistrictgo.org/transit-talk-were-in-it-together/"&gt;https://udistrictgo.org/transit-talk-were-in-it-together/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="General"></category><category term="Transportation"></category><category term="Pedestrian"></category></entry><entry><title>Vibrant Art Coming Soon to Aurora Ave N Pedestrian Bridge</title><link href="https://lovelicton.com/vibrant-art-aurora-2018.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-10-16T23:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-10-16T23:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>amandacrosley</name></author><id>tag:lovelicton.com,2018-10-16:/vibrant-art-aurora-2018.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Aurora Ave N corridor is about to see some welcome color and vibrancy on its pedestrian bridge at N 102nd St. Crews will be focused on cleaning and painting the pedestrian bridge through the next three weeks. The pedestrian bridge will be open during cleaning and painting, although a …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Aurora Ave N corridor is about to see some welcome color and vibrancy on its pedestrian bridge at N 102nd St. Crews will be focused on cleaning and painting the pedestrian bridge through the next three weeks. The pedestrian bridge will be open during cleaning and painting, although a worker may escort you through the work zone. There may be temporary bridge closures. In six to eight weeks, &lt;a href="http://vickiscuri.com/project-aurora.html"&gt;Vicki Scuri's art installation&lt;/a&gt; will be installed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-style: italic"&gt;Inspired by the sunrise, this project adds color and pattern to an aging pedestrian bridge, transforming it into a community landmark gateway. Hundreds of translucent colorful fins transition through the hues of the sunrise across the span of the bridge. The four foot tall and six and half inch wide fins sit on the outside of and attach to the railings. The fins elevate the bridge into a unique art experience for both the cars traveling under and the pedestrians above. The colors on the translucent fins will shift and blend as the viewer moves through the site, creating a dynamic experience. The bridge's columns and stair hold colorful painted graphic, connecting the artwork directly to the site.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/aurora/bridge_project.png"&gt;&lt;img alt="Aurora Bridge Art Installation" src="/images/aurora/bridge_project.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project was funded by the Neighborhood Street Fund program to enhance safety and add visual identity for the Aurora-Licton Urban Village.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Visit the project's webpage at&lt;a href="https://eur02.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.seattle.gov%2Ftransportation%2FNSFAuroraCorridor.htm&amp;amp;data=02%7C01%7C%7Cb39d53c3a9fe4d92b1c408d62fa1843a%7C84df9e7fe9f640afb435aaaaaaaaaaaa%7C1%7C0%7C636748768081473305&amp;amp;sdata=c%2FrGcXAr3ROcaqkIDJlr70ROeIaVkbltt%2BiuQVBmqAk%3D&amp;amp;reserved=0"&gt; www.seattle.gov/transportation/NSFAuroraCorridor.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;to learn more or sign up for the project's&lt;a href="https://eur02.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fel2.envirolytical.com%2Fregistration%2Fform%2F28731&amp;amp;data=02%7C01%7C%7Cb39d53c3a9fe4d92b1c408d62fa1843a%7C84df9e7fe9f640afb435aaaaaaaaaaaa%7C1%7C0%7C636748768081473305&amp;amp;sdata=pJ5D1IGP%2BFv43JEewPDsWrWSZDmNQ4nQfmaFTTxfilA%3D&amp;amp;reserved=0"&gt; email list&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="General"></category><category term="Improvements"></category><category term="Transit"></category><category term="Pedestrian"></category><category term="Art"></category></entry><entry><title>Looking for Volunteers for the Licton Springs Halloween Walk</title><link href="https://lovelicton.com/looking-for-halloween-volunteers-2018.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-10-08T20:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-10-08T20:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>timothycrosley</name></author><id>tag:lovelicton.com,2018-10-08:/looking-for-halloween-volunteers-2018.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hi Neighbors!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A friend of the blog reached out to us to let us know that this year's Halloween Walk is looking for volunteers:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are looking to recruit Friends of the Forest for this year's Licton Springs Halloween Walk - Do you or anyone you know like to dress up …&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hi Neighbors!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A friend of the blog reached out to us to let us know that this year's Halloween Walk is looking for volunteers:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are looking to recruit Friends of the Forest for this year's Licton Springs Halloween Walk - Do you or anyone you know like to dress up and give out treats? (The treats are provided.) Are your kids older and you miss seeing the young ones dressed up? Groups are welcome. You must be at least 12 years old to be a Friend or parents with children. Please contact Melanie at 206-227-9155 or email &lt;a href="mailto: melaniedavies81@gmail.com"&gt;melaniedavies81@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt; if you can volunteer. The time commitment is from 4:15 to 6 pm. Hot cider provided.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/events/2018/october/halloween.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Halloween" src="/images/events/2018/october/halloween.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="General"></category><category term="Community"></category><category term="Event"></category><category term="Outdoors"></category><category term="Parks"></category><category term="Volunteers"></category></entry><entry><title>Neighbors Work Together to Build Urban Forest</title><link href="https://lovelicton.com/licton-springs-urban-forest.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-10-07T20:25:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-10-07T20:25:00-07:00</updated><author><name>timothycrosley</name></author><id>tag:lovelicton.com,2018-10-07:/licton-springs-urban-forest.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Yesterday morning several neighbors came together at 85th and Meridian to clear away invasive weeds (looking at you blackberries!) and make way for an urban forest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src="https://www.google.com/maps/d/u/0/embed?mid=1lnw8u4FFAVjzc5YzbP4n1L7i5pPzbiXp" width="640" height="480"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The work party was the second such event at the site and made significant progress:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/trees/october.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Progress Made 1" src="/images/trees/october.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/trees/june_1.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Progress Made 2" src="/images/trees/june_1.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/trees/june_2.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Progress Made 3" src="/images/trees/june_2.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Planting trees in the area, which borders an I5 …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Yesterday morning several neighbors came together at 85th and Meridian to clear away invasive weeds (looking at you blackberries!) and make way for an urban forest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src="https://www.google.com/maps/d/u/0/embed?mid=1lnw8u4FFAVjzc5YzbP4n1L7i5pPzbiXp" width="640" height="480"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The work party was the second such event at the site and made significant progress:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/trees/october.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Progress Made 1" src="/images/trees/october.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/trees/june_1.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Progress Made 2" src="/images/trees/june_1.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/trees/june_2.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Progress Made 3" src="/images/trees/june_2.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Planting trees in the area, which borders an I5 off-ramp, will have a large positive impact on the neighborhood as highways and their ramps are a major source of pollution and noise. Trees have been shown to &lt;a href="https://www.healthguidance.org/entry/8525/1/Trees-And-Shrubs-Can-Curb-Noise.html"&gt;reduce highway noise&lt;/a&gt; while &lt;a href="https://www.fastcompany.com/3022137/dont-like-pollution-in-your-home-plant-a-row-of-trees-and-breath-easier-by-half"&gt;cutting pollution by half&lt;/a&gt;. The trees will work in tandem with the noise wall put in place in 2009 along I5 itself, to make Licton Springs a quieter and healthier neighborhood for all of us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hope to see you at the next work party!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="General"></category><category term="Greenery"></category><category term="Trees"></category><category term="Quality of Life"></category></entry><entry><title>Pumpkin Spice &amp; Everything Nice: October Community Events</title><link href="https://lovelicton.com/october-events-2018.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-10-02T18:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-10-02T18:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>amandacrosley</name></author><id>tag:lovelicton.com,2018-10-02:/october-events-2018.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Goblins, Witches, and Ghosts, OH MY! October is here! Check out some of the upcoming Licton Springs events this month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Social &amp;amp; Networking Events:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thursday, October 4th, @ 4:30PM, &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/185311612365952/"&gt;Lantern Brewing Business Social&lt;/a&gt;, Lantern Brewing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/events/2018/october/lantern.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Lantern Brewing" src="/images/events/2018/october/lantern.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn about the brewing industry and meet other local businesses!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Saturday, October 13th @ 4PM-10PM, &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/266508717336840/"&gt;Asian Street …&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Goblins, Witches, and Ghosts, OH MY! October is here! Check out some of the upcoming Licton Springs events this month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Social &amp;amp; Networking Events:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thursday, October 4th, @ 4:30PM, &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/185311612365952/"&gt;Lantern Brewing Business Social&lt;/a&gt;, Lantern Brewing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/events/2018/october/lantern.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Lantern Brewing" src="/images/events/2018/october/lantern.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn about the brewing industry and meet other local businesses!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Saturday, October 13th @ 4PM-10PM, &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/266508717336840/"&gt;Asian Street Food Night Market&lt;/a&gt;, Northgate Mall&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/events/2018/october/street_food.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Asian Street Food" src="/images/events/2018/october/street_food.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;($7 for 1 ticket, $25 for 4 tickets, and $45 for 8 tickets).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;20+ local Asian Vendors will be cooking and serving over 100 different types of Asian dishes and snacks, including Chinese Crepes, dumplings, bobas, skewers, fruit teas, dessert and so many more!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our vendors lineup include the popular Vong's Kitchen, Spicy City, Happy Lemon, Tokyo Trendy, Mee Sum, Peony, Yummy Duck, Kungfu Jianbing, Banana Kingdom, and more to be added!
There will also live performances and fun games on site for your enjoyment!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sunday, October 14th @ 8:30AM, &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/196387857883349/"&gt;Cascade Orienteering Club: Choose Your Adventure&lt;/a&gt;, North Seattle College&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/events/2018/october/orienteering.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Choose Your Own Adventure" src="/images/events/2018/october/orienteering.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Choose Your Adventure series is designed to be extra fun, social, and friendly for beginners, yet interesting for seasoned veterans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At Choose Your Adventure events, everyone gets the same map with 24 checkpoints marked all over it. Then, after a mass start, you can find as many checkpoints as you want, in whichever order you want! Just be sure to mind the time, since there’s also a time limit. Return to the finish on-time, or lose precious points for every minute you’re late.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Monday, October 15th @ 6PM, &lt;a href="https://www.meetup.com/North-Seattle-Tech-Talks/events/253170186/"&gt;Security Considerations in Software Design &amp;amp; Implementation North Seattle Tech Talks&lt;/a&gt;, North Seattle College, Room CC1161&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/events/2018/october/north_seattle.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="North Seattle Tech Talks" src="/images/events/2018/october/north_seattle.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seattle technology enthusiasts, students, and professionals are invited to join us for North Seattle Tech Talks. We'll gather for informative, insightful, inspiring, and inclusive talks on topics in web development, mobile apps, cloud computing technologies, and professional development. Follow up each Meetup with a chance to ask questions, socialize, and meet folks interested in the Seattle tech scene.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Saturday, October 27 @ 4:00PM, &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/244177149775585/"&gt;Doom Zoom - Zoom Room Halloween Party&lt;/a&gt;, Zoom Room Dog Training&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/events/2018/october/zoom_room.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Doom Zoom" src="/images/events/2018/october/zoom_room.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;($15)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's time for our annual Halloween Party! Cheryl will be busting out her homemade chili and there will food and drink for man and beast!
Contest and prizes for Best Costume, Best Team Costume and Best Trick! So start planning early!
Boo Boo's Boosters will be sponsoring the trick contest and the winner goes home with a stash of Boosters!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Saturday &amp;amp; Sunday, October 27th and 28th, &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/931117210419261/"&gt;55th Annual Wild Mushroom Show&lt;/a&gt;, North Seattle Community College, Old Cafeteria&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/events/2018/october/mushrooms.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Mushrooms!" src="/images/events/2018/october/mushrooms.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Wild Mushroom Show is one of the largest and most complete
exhibits of mushrooms in the United States. Over 200 varieties of wild
mushrooms will be displayed, identified, and classified as edible, poisonous, or valueless as food.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$10 Adults, $5 students, 12 &amp;amp; under are free.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wednesday, October 31st @ 4:30PM, &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/308149439973556/"&gt;Licton Springs Halloween&lt;/a&gt;, Licton Springs Park&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/events/2018/october/halloween.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Halloween" src="/images/events/2018/october/halloween.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Walk the park path and meet the Friends of the Forest while collecting treats and treasures. Hot cider and music at the playground!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Community Engagement Events:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wednesday, October 3rd @ 6PM, &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/AuroraLicton/photos/a.1615736478744149/2125206947797097/?type=3&amp;amp;theater"&gt;Seattle Public Utilities Sharps Training&lt;/a&gt;, Epic Life Church&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All are welcome, including those not affiliated with the neighborhood. No RSVP required. If you have questions, contact Alison Steinbacher at &lt;a href="mailto:alison.steinbacher@seattle.gov"&gt;alison.steinbacher@seattle.gov&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wednesday, October 3rd, @ 7PM, &lt;a href="http://seattlenpac.blogspot.com/"&gt;Seattle North Precinct Advisory Council&lt;/a&gt;, Cascadia Elementary School&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The North Precinct Advisory Council is a community organization devoted to promoting partnership between residents, schools, businesses, and the Seattle Police Department to effectively address public safety issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Saturday, October 6th, @ 9AM, &lt;a href="https://www.surveymonkey.com/r/85thMeridianOct6"&gt;Trees for Seattle Licton Springs Work Party&lt;/a&gt;, 85th &amp;amp; Meridian&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Help neighbors clean up the gateway to the community!  Volunteers will be removing the invasive weeds that threaten the area's beautiful trees. This is a great opportunity to make your mark on a landscape that needs some love while connecting with friends and neighbors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tuesday, October 9th @ 6PM, &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/288493891879891"&gt;Mineral Springs Park Community Meeting&lt;/a&gt;, Neighborcare Health at Meridian&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Discuss Mineral Springs Park events, work parties, and community engagement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thursday, October 11th @ 7PM, &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/AuroraLicton"&gt;ALUV Monthly Meeting&lt;/a&gt;, Epic Life Church&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ALUV stands for Aurora Licton Urban Village and seeks to build a pedestrian-safe, visually vibrant, economically sound, livable, and welcoming urban village using sustainable-growth principles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Saturday, October 13th @ 10AM, &lt;a href="https://lictonsprings.org/work_party.pdf"&gt;Friends of Licton Springs Park Clean Up&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Join FRIENDS OF LICTON SPRINGS for our monthly work parties&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wednesday, October 17th @ 6:30PM, &lt;a href="https://lictonsprings.org/"&gt;Licton Springs Community Council Meeting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Join Licton Springs Community Council for our monthly meeting&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To stay up to date on other activities coming up, check out LoveLicton's &lt;a href="https://lovelicton.com/pages/community-calendar.html"&gt;calendar&lt;/a&gt;.  Hope to see you at an upcoming event!
Did we miss something? Let us know in the comments below!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="General"></category><category term="Community Meeting"></category><category term="Event"></category><category term="Outdoors"></category><category term="Parks"></category><category term="Tech"></category></entry><entry><title>Feedback requested along Aurora</title><link href="https://lovelicton.com/aurora-litter-abatement-feedback.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-09-30T23:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-09-30T23:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>timothycrosley</name></author><id>tag:lovelicton.com,2018-09-30:/aurora-litter-abatement-feedback.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;As we &lt;a href="https://lovelicton.com/aurora-is-getting-cleaned-up.html"&gt;reported&lt;/a&gt; back in May, Seattle Public Utilities (SPU) added Licton Springs along Aurora Ave. to its pilot list of twice-weekly cleanup locations. Now SPU is asking residents and businesses in the area for their thoughts on the effectiveness of the Litter Abatement Pilot Program and the additional 2x …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As we &lt;a href="https://lovelicton.com/aurora-is-getting-cleaned-up.html"&gt;reported&lt;/a&gt; back in May, Seattle Public Utilities (SPU) added Licton Springs along Aurora Ave. to its pilot list of twice-weekly cleanup locations. Now SPU is asking residents and businesses in the area for their thoughts on the effectiveness of the Litter Abatement Pilot Program and the additional 2x/week litter cleanup it has provided. The survey seeks community thoughts on how they feel about cleanliness in their neighborhoods to determine next steps on the Litter Pilot Program. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.surveymonkey.com/r/lictonspringslitter"&gt;Take the survey here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, if you live, work, or travel through Nesbit Ave. N. between N 88th to N 90th streets:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/aurora/nesbit.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Nesbit Survey Area" src="/images/aurora/nesbit.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;then &lt;a href="https://www.sngi.org/welcome/index.php"&gt;Seattle Neighborhood Group&lt;/a&gt; would like to know about any safety concerns you have, via &lt;a href="https://www.surveymonkey.com/r/SNGnesbit"&gt;this survey&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="General"></category><category term="Surveys"></category><category term="Aurora"></category><category term="Safety"></category></entry><entry><title>Licton Springs Tiny House Village will close permanently March 2019</title><link href="https://lovelicton.com/licton-springs-tiny-house-village-to-close.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-09-26T20:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-09-26T20:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>timothycrosley</name></author><id>tag:lovelicton.com,2018-09-26:/licton-springs-tiny-house-village-to-close.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;We learned today that the controversial Aurora Ave. tiny house village within Licton Springs will be closing for good March of next year. While many members of the local community have voiced their support for helping the least fortunate among us and have diligently donated food to the village, there …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We learned today that the controversial Aurora Ave. tiny house village within Licton Springs will be closing for good March of next year. While many members of the local community have voiced their support for helping the least fortunate among us and have diligently donated food to the village, there has been disagreement that the village as designed is the best route to solve the problem. Since its creation there have been many complaints of crime that have been attributed to the village as well as a general concern around having an official policy of allowing illicit drug use just blocks from 3 schools, 2 of which are for elementary aged children.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the &lt;a href="https://homelessness.seattle.gov/tiny-house-village-update-next-steps-for-licton-springs/"&gt;city's homeless response blog&lt;/a&gt;, they identify finding permanent houses for the remaining residents as the top priority of the site ahead of its closure, with additional case management and partner agencies brought in to expedite the process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Perspectives from around the web on the closure:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.seattletimes.com/seattle-news/homeless/controversial-tiny-house-village-for-homelessness-in-north-seattle-to-close/"&gt;SeattleTimes: Controversial tiny house village for homelessness in North Seattle to close&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.kuow.org/stories/tiny-house-village-on-aurora-set-to-close"&gt;KUOW: Tiny house village on Aurora Ave set to close&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.kiro7.com/news/local/seattle-to-close-controversial-tiny-house-encampment/841945703"&gt;KIRO: Seattle to close controversial tiny house encampment&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.king5.com/article/news/local/homeless/controversial-tiny-house-village-for-seattle-homeless-to-close/281-598435383"&gt;King 5: Controversial tiny house village for Seattle homeless to close&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.thestranger.com/slog/2018/09/26/32946409/slog-pm-aurora-avenue-tiny-house-village-slated-for-closure-bomb-threat-in-olympia-this-kayaker-got-bitch-slapped-by-nature"&gt;The Stranger/SLOG: NIMBYs get their way, tiny house village closes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><category term="General"></category><category term="Homeless"></category></entry><entry><title>City Council Unanimously Passes Aurora Licton Urban Village Moratorium Extension</title><link href="https://lovelicton.com/aurora-zone-controls-extension-2018-approval.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-09-24T20:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-09-24T20:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>timothycrosley</name></author><id>tag:lovelicton.com,2018-09-24:/aurora-zone-controls-extension-2018-approval.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today after extensive community feedback (at least 100 proponents of the moratorium and five against it) Seattle City Council unanimously passed a 6-month extension of its moratorium for new non-pedestrian-oriented developments within the Aurora Licton Urban Village:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/nUVB4JXMIHE?rel=0&amp;amp;start=6805&amp;amp;end=7149" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; encrypted-media" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The extension represents a victory for the &lt;a href="http://auroralictonuv.org/"&gt;ALUV group&lt;/a&gt; and associated members of …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today after extensive community feedback (at least 100 proponents of the moratorium and five against it) Seattle City Council unanimously passed a 6-month extension of its moratorium for new non-pedestrian-oriented developments within the Aurora Licton Urban Village:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/nUVB4JXMIHE?rel=0&amp;amp;start=6805&amp;amp;end=7149" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; encrypted-media" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The extension represents a victory for the &lt;a href="http://auroralictonuv.org/"&gt;ALUV group&lt;/a&gt; and associated members of the community who want to see Aurora transform into the center of a pedestrian friendly neighborhood that does its part to help soften our ongoing housing crises.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="General"></category><category term="Zoning"></category><category term="Pedestrian"></category><category term="Business"></category></entry><entry><title>Aurora Licton Urban Village Moratorium Extension Passes First Hurdle</title><link href="https://lovelicton.com/aurora-zone-controls-extension-2018-update.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-09-19T20:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-09-19T20:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>timothycrosley</name></author><id>tag:lovelicton.com,2018-09-19:/aurora-zone-controls-extension-2018-update.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today Seattle's Planning, Land Use, and Zoning Committee adopted a 6 Month extension on its moratorium for new non-pedestrian-oriented developments within the Aurora Licton Urban Village:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/lTLxqxo6q_Y?rel=0&amp;amp;start=2520&amp;amp;end=3223" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; encrypted-media" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This leaves the final fate of the extension to Seattle City Council with a vote coming up this following Monday (the 24th of September …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today Seattle's Planning, Land Use, and Zoning Committee adopted a 6 Month extension on its moratorium for new non-pedestrian-oriented developments within the Aurora Licton Urban Village:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/lTLxqxo6q_Y?rel=0&amp;amp;start=2520&amp;amp;end=3223" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; encrypted-media" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This leaves the final fate of the extension to Seattle City Council with a vote coming up this following Monday (the 24th of September).
If you have thoughts on the extension and have not yet made them heard, this represents your final opportunity, and I encourage you to follow the steps &lt;a href="http://auroralictonuv.org/2018/08/28/interim-controls-extension/"&gt;ALUV has outlined&lt;/a&gt; to contact your representatives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The committee's adoption of the ordinance followed significant feedback from our local community during their September 5 meeting:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/6rza2LUi6xY?rel=0&amp;amp;start=870&amp;amp;end=2040" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; encrypted-media" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, the first new proposed residential apartment project in some time within our Urban Village is actively &lt;a href="https://designreview.info/"&gt;gathering feedback&lt;/a&gt; up till the 26th of this month.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="General"></category><category term="Zoning"></category><category term="Pedestrian"></category><category term="Business"></category></entry><entry><title>Outdoor Movie Night and Dog Pawty was a SUCCESS!</title><link href="https://lovelicton.com/outdoor_dog_pawty_and_movie_night_success.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-09-15T23:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-09-15T23:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>timothycrosley</name></author><id>tag:lovelicton.com,2018-09-15:/outdoor_dog_pawty_and_movie_night_success.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Thanks to everyone that braved the rain and came out last night. We had so much fun watching Isle of Dogs with all of you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We wanted to share some of our favorite highlights from the event:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/events/2018/september/dog_pawty/1.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Dog Pawty Image" src="/images/events/2018/september/dog_pawty/1.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/events/2018/september/dog_pawty/2.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Dog Pawty Image" src="/images/events/2018/september/dog_pawty/2.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/events/2018/september/dog_pawty/3.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Dog Pawty Image" src="/images/events/2018/september/dog_pawty/3.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/events/2018/september/dog_pawty/4.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Dog Pawty Image" src="/images/events/2018/september/dog_pawty/4.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/events/2018/september/dog_pawty/5.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Dog Pawty Image" src="/images/events/2018/september/dog_pawty/5.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/events/2018/september/dog_pawty/6.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Dog Pawty Image" src="/images/events/2018/september/dog_pawty/6.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/events/2018/september/dog_pawty/7.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Dog Pawty Image" src="/images/events/2018/september/dog_pawty/7.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/events/2018/september/dog_pawty/8.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Dog Pawty Image" src="/images/events/2018/september/dog_pawty/8.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/events/2018/september/dog_pawty/10.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Dog Pawty Image" src="/images/events/2018/september/dog_pawty/10.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/events/2018/september/dog_pawty/9.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Dog Pawty Image" src="/images/events/2018/september/dog_pawty/9.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/events/2018/september/dog_pawty/11.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Dog Pawty Image" src="/images/events/2018/september/dog_pawty/11.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/events/2018/september/dog_pawty/12.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Dog Pawty Image" src="/images/events/2018/september/dog_pawty/12.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/events/2018/september/dog_pawty/13.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Dog Pawty Image" src="/images/events/2018/september/dog_pawty/13.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/events/2018/september/dog_pawty/14.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Dog Pawty Image" src="/images/events/2018/september/dog_pawty/14.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/events/2018/september/dog_pawty/15.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Dog Pawty Image" src="/images/events/2018/september/dog_pawty/15.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/events/2018/september/dog_pawty/16.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Dog Pawty Image" src="/images/events/2018/september/dog_pawty/16.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/events/2018/september/dog_pawty/17.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Dog Pawty Image" src="/images/events/2018/september/dog_pawty/17.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/events/2018/september/dog_pawty/18.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Dog Pawty Image" src="/images/events/2018/september/dog_pawty/18.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/events/2018/september/dog_pawty/19.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Dog Pawty Image" src="/images/events/2018/september/dog_pawty/19.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And again: many thanks to the sponsors that helped make this event possible …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Thanks to everyone that braved the rain and came out last night. We had so much fun watching Isle of Dogs with all of you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We wanted to share some of our favorite highlights from the event:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/events/2018/september/dog_pawty/1.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Dog Pawty Image" src="/images/events/2018/september/dog_pawty/1.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/events/2018/september/dog_pawty/2.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Dog Pawty Image" src="/images/events/2018/september/dog_pawty/2.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/events/2018/september/dog_pawty/3.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Dog Pawty Image" src="/images/events/2018/september/dog_pawty/3.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/events/2018/september/dog_pawty/4.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Dog Pawty Image" src="/images/events/2018/september/dog_pawty/4.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/events/2018/september/dog_pawty/5.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Dog Pawty Image" src="/images/events/2018/september/dog_pawty/5.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/events/2018/september/dog_pawty/6.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Dog Pawty Image" src="/images/events/2018/september/dog_pawty/6.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/events/2018/september/dog_pawty/7.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Dog Pawty Image" src="/images/events/2018/september/dog_pawty/7.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/events/2018/september/dog_pawty/8.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Dog Pawty Image" src="/images/events/2018/september/dog_pawty/8.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/events/2018/september/dog_pawty/10.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Dog Pawty Image" src="/images/events/2018/september/dog_pawty/10.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/events/2018/september/dog_pawty/9.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Dog Pawty Image" src="/images/events/2018/september/dog_pawty/9.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/events/2018/september/dog_pawty/11.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Dog Pawty Image" src="/images/events/2018/september/dog_pawty/11.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/events/2018/september/dog_pawty/12.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Dog Pawty Image" src="/images/events/2018/september/dog_pawty/12.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/events/2018/september/dog_pawty/13.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Dog Pawty Image" src="/images/events/2018/september/dog_pawty/13.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/events/2018/september/dog_pawty/14.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Dog Pawty Image" src="/images/events/2018/september/dog_pawty/14.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/events/2018/september/dog_pawty/15.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Dog Pawty Image" src="/images/events/2018/september/dog_pawty/15.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/events/2018/september/dog_pawty/16.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Dog Pawty Image" src="/images/events/2018/september/dog_pawty/16.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/events/2018/september/dog_pawty/17.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Dog Pawty Image" src="/images/events/2018/september/dog_pawty/17.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/events/2018/september/dog_pawty/18.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Dog Pawty Image" src="/images/events/2018/september/dog_pawty/18.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/events/2018/september/dog_pawty/19.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Dog Pawty Image" src="/images/events/2018/september/dog_pawty/19.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And again: many thanks to the sponsors that helped make this event possible!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.seattle.gov/parks"&gt;Seattle Parks &amp;amp; Recreation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/downtowndoglounge/"&gt;Downtown Dog Lounge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/rooseveltstationvet/"&gt;Roosevelt Station Vet Care&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/PupCakes-LLC-258376214180526/"&gt;PupCakes, LLC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/barkbox/"&gt;BarkBox&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/TheBrewmastersBakery/"&gt;The BrewMaster's Bakery&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/bluedogbakerytreats/"&gt;Blue Dog Bakery&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/lovebugpetmassage/"&gt;Love Bug Pet Massage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/RXBAR/"&gt;RXBAR&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/SparklingIce/"&gt;Sparkling Ice&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/LunchboxLab/"&gt;Lunchbox Laboratory&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/HelloFreshus/"&gt;HelloFresh&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://lovelicton.com"&gt;LoveLicton&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/MineralSpringsSeattle/"&gt;Friends Of Mineral Springs Park&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/events/2018/september/dog_pawty/20.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Dog Pawty Image" src="/images/events/2018/september/dog_pawty/20.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/events/2018/september/dog_pawty/23.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Dog Pawty Image" src="/images/events/2018/september/dog_pawty/23.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/events/2018/september/dog_pawty/24.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Dog Pawty Image" src="/images/events/2018/september/dog_pawty/24.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/events/2018/september/dog_pawty/25.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Dog Pawty Image" src="/images/events/2018/september/dog_pawty/25.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, we want to thank all of our neighbors who lent us their tents, time, and hands. This event couldn't have been successful without you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/events/2018/september/dog_pawty/21.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Dog Pawty Image" src="/images/events/2018/september/dog_pawty/21.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/events/2018/september/dog_pawty/22.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Dog Pawty Image" src="/images/events/2018/september/dog_pawty/22.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hope to see everyone at a future event!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="General"></category><category term="Community Meeting"></category><category term="Event"></category><category term="Outdoors"></category><category term="Parks"></category><category term="Dogs"></category><category term="Movies"></category></entry><entry><title>Outdoor Movie Night and Dog Pawty TONIGHT at 6PM</title><link href="https://lovelicton.com/outdoor_dog_pawty_and_movie_night.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-09-15T15:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-09-15T15:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>timothycrosley</name></author><id>tag:lovelicton.com,2018-09-15:/outdoor_dog_pawty_and_movie_night.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The FREE Outdoor Movie Night and Dog Pawty is TONIGHT!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/events/2018/september/dog_pawty.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Outdoor Movie and Dog Pawty!" src="/images/events/2018/september/dog_pawty.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rain or shine the show must go on! We will have tents up in case of rain and encourage attendees to bring a rain jacket and lawn chair and/or blanket.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The event is being held at Mineral Springs Park …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The FREE Outdoor Movie Night and Dog Pawty is TONIGHT!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/events/2018/september/dog_pawty.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Outdoor Movie and Dog Pawty!" src="/images/events/2018/september/dog_pawty.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rain or shine the show must go on! We will have tents up in case of rain and encourage attendees to bring a rain jacket and lawn chair and/or blanket.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The event is being held at Mineral Springs Park:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src="https://www.google.com/maps/embed?pb=!1m18!1m12!1m3!1d2684.9091983501103!2d-122.33884308449383!3d47.70560037919132!2m3!1f0!2f0!3f0!3m2!1i1024!2i768!4f13.1!3m3!1m2!1s0x549016ac993479d9%3A0xf98a47209074cbc!2sMineral+Springs+Park!5e0!3m2!1sen!2sus!4v1537046867806" width="600" height="450" frameborder="0" style="border:0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There will be FREE drinks, popcorn, &amp;amp; snacks provided by our sponsors! Vendors and dog contests being at 6:00 PM and Isle of Dogs is planned to start at 7:30 PM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/mineral_springs/isle_of_dogs.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Isle of Dogs FREE movie" src="/images/mineral_springs/isle_of_dogs.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is still time to sign up your dog for one of the contests: "Best Dog Trick", "Best Dog Costume", and "Miss/Mr. Congeniality" &lt;a href="http://bit.ly/seattledogcontest"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and there will be a chance to sign up in person at the event as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many thanks to our sponsors for helping make this event possible!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.seattle.gov/parks"&gt;Seattle Parks &amp;amp; Recreation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/downtowndoglounge/"&gt;Downtown Dog Lounge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/rooseveltstationvet/"&gt;Roosevelt Station Vet Care&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/PupCakes-LLC-258376214180526/"&gt;PupCakes, LLC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/barkbox/"&gt;BarkBox&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/TheBrewmastersBakery/"&gt;The BrewMaster's Bakery&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/bluedogbakerytreats/"&gt;Blue Dog Bakery&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/lovebugpetmassage/"&gt;Love Bug Pet Massage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/RXBAR/"&gt;RXBAR&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/SparklingIce/"&gt;Sparkling Ice&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/LunchboxLab/"&gt;Lunchbox Laboratory&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/HelloFreshus/"&gt;HelloFresh&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://lovelicton.com"&gt;LoveLicton&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/MineralSpringsSeattle/"&gt;Friends Of Mineral Springs Park&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hope to see you there!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="General"></category><category term="Community Meeting"></category><category term="Event"></category><category term="Outdoors"></category><category term="Parks"></category><category term="Dogs"></category><category term="Movies"></category></entry><entry><title>Happening now: Licton Springs PPatch 5th Anniversary</title><link href="https://lovelicton.com/ppatch-5th-anniversary.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-09-15T13:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-09-15T13:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>timothycrosley</name></author><id>tag:lovelicton.com,2018-09-15:/ppatch-5th-anniversary.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;REMINDER: Licton Springs PPatch 5th anniversary is happening NOW until 3PM&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/318018722104303/"&gt;&lt;img alt="P-Patch 5th Anniversary Party!" src="/images/events/2018/september/ppatch_party.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Join neighbors at the P-Patch (92nd and Meridian - the south edge of North Seattle College campus):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Demonstrations and Q&amp;amp;A&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bishop Blanchet Beekeepers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;North Seattle College Botany Class Pollinator Garden&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kiss Activities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Potluck&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recipes From the Garden&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;REMINDER: Licton Springs PPatch 5th anniversary is happening NOW until 3PM&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/318018722104303/"&gt;&lt;img alt="P-Patch 5th Anniversary Party!" src="/images/events/2018/september/ppatch_party.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Join neighbors at the P-Patch (92nd and Meridian - the south edge of North Seattle College campus):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Demonstrations and Q&amp;amp;A&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bishop Blanchet Beekeepers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;North Seattle College Botany Class Pollinator Garden&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kiss Activities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Potluck&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recipes From the Garden&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><category term="General"></category><category term="Community Meeting"></category><category term="Event"></category><category term="Outdoors"></category><category term="Parks"></category><category term="PPatch"></category></entry><entry><title>Home Zone Meeting Gathers Valuable Community Input</title><link href="https://lovelicton.com/home-zone-2018-meeting-1.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-09-14T18:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-09-14T18:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>timothycrosley</name></author><id>tag:lovelicton.com,2018-09-14:/home-zone-2018-meeting-1.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Yesterday around 50 Licton Springs neighbors came together to provide input for the upcoming Home Zone pilot that targets the Southeast corner of Licton Springs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/homezone/meeting.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Home Zone meeting draws in community" src="/images/homezone/meeting.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a brief introduction about the desire of the pilot and the inherent limitations due to a small budget size, neighbors split up into groups …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Yesterday around 50 Licton Springs neighbors came together to provide input for the upcoming Home Zone pilot that targets the Southeast corner of Licton Springs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/homezone/meeting.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Home Zone meeting draws in community" src="/images/homezone/meeting.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a brief introduction about the desire of the pilot and the inherent limitations due to a small budget size, neighbors split up into groups to separately tackle traffic calming, community art, and wayfinding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the meeting the following existing areas of concern were identified:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Significant and fast cut-through traffic through both Meridian and Corliss which, combined with lack of sidewalks, causes an impediment to pedestrian activity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fast traffic is coming down the hill from 90th and Meridian to 90th and Burke. This area already has a lot of pedestrian activity, but speed combined with the lack of a safe intersection has already led to a collision and many near collisions with both pedestrians and other vehicles.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Non-ideal crossing conditions at 90th and Wallingford. A child who attended the meeting shared their story of near collision occurring just a few days prior. Other areas near the school have flashing pedestrian signs, but this intersection lacks them.
Proposal being explained&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/homezone/explain.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Proposal being explained" src="/images/homezone/explain.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the meeting, there was also concern expressed around a previous proposal to close Meridian off at 92nd with a "Do Not Enter" sign. Much of the concern centered around the fact that closing off the street could move the traffic onto other roads, in particular, Corliss, while not addressing walkability. This lined up well with much of the Anonymous feedback we received from our online &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLScAtYcX8J4IQE_agDKW45oXHEvzt0LaOTQ1lImnO8CdkqSScg/viewform?usp=pp_url&amp;amp;entry.1991292058=Yes"&gt;survey&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't understand the problem this is fixing. Closing Meridian does nothing for the 90th Street Burke hill, through which half the neighborhood drains out,
 will make the backup at 92nd &amp;amp; College worse, while causing daily irritation and delay for the other half of the neighborhood in getting home (or causing
 them to speed down the hill on 90th north of Meridian, too). Traffic calming on the Burke hill I'm all in favor of, but don't understand the benefit for the
rest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With regard to the current proposal, at 92nd and Meridian I would prefer that it be a "local access only" sign instead of a one-way street / do not enter
sign.
I like the idea for the street planters, stop signs, speed bump at 90th and burke, and the street art at 88th and burke.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The North Greenwood traffic calming maze is a nightmare. What do the residents over there think about having to drive many more blocks to get where they want or the increased east/west traffic down their formerly quiet residential streets?
So I am skeptical about the proposed Home Pilot Program. The plan that the people living at the north end of Meridian to get home from College Way now,
instead of a left turn, one block, right turn and into driveway, will be making a right turn, one block, stop, left turn 2 blocks, stop, left turn 2 blocks
stop, left turn, weave among planters and finally home. Also, since I live on Corliss, I'm not happy at the prospect of increased traffic from cars trying to
get to Meridian from the East. There are a LOT of pedestrians, (students, elderly, young families, dog walkers) that use our sidewalk-less street. I plan to
make a count on a weekday to corroborate that statement. Are not the proposals to close off access to 85th at Meridian and put a stop sign at 90th sufficient to really cut down traffic volumes and speed?
A Local Access Only sign at 92nd and Corliss is fairly meaningless.
I hope you put the walking sign at the corner of the school grounds and not in someone's front yard.
The speed bump crosswalk at N. 90th and Burke is fine if it is something the people in the houses at that corner feel is necessary. It is a residential
intersection at the bottom of a steep hill with parked cars often making progress to Wallingford slow anyway. Cars SHOULD be crawling there.
As for the proposed art, no comment until I see what and where.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like many of the ideas (stop signs and planters on Meridian Ave N), with the exception of blocking southbound access to Meridian Ave N at N 92nd street.
The reason for not preferring this option is that in wintertime during snow conditions southbound access provides a safer route home (avoiding steep hills)
and that blocking access would lengthen the drive through residential neighborhoods to get to my home.  My observation is that most of the problem with fast
cars driving through the neighborhood in the morning is due to northbound cars (not southbound cars). Thanks for your consideration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After discussion, the community seemed to coalesce around the idea of working to limit speed on both Meridian and Corliss with inexpensive traffic calming measures, rather than entirely block access.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many ideas were brought up to increase the walkability of the area including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Intersection art at 90th and Burke Ave N. The hope is that this would clearly mark the intersection encouraging vehicles to slow down and yield for pedestrians.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wayfinding signs in various forms throughout the neighborhood.
&lt;a href="/images/homezone/wayfinding.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Wayfinding signs" src="/images/homezone/wayfinding.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Traffic calming measures, such as strategically placed planters and/or chicanes, evenly applied on both Meridian and Corliss.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Setting up a weekly &lt;a href="https://www.seattle.gov/transportation/projects-and-programs/programs/public-space-management-programs/play-streets"&gt;play street&lt;/a&gt; on one of the unsidewalked blocks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pedestrian activated crosswalk on 90th and Wallingford.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the immediate next steps focused on art and wayfinding as traffic calming requires permit approval from SDOT and will take more time to put in place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is still plenty of time to provide feedback or get involved! To do so &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLScAtYcX8J4IQE_agDKW45oXHEvzt0LaOTQ1lImnO8CdkqSScg/viewform?entry.1991292058=Yes"&gt;take the survey&lt;/a&gt; or email &lt;a href="mailto:meridianhomezone@gmail.com"&gt;meridianhomezone@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt;. You can also keep up with the latest on the home zone at &lt;a href="http://bit.ly/walkzone"&gt;bit.ly/walkzone&lt;/a&gt; which I'll do my best to update as more input is gathered and proposals are modified or implemented.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="General"></category><category term="Pedestrian"></category><category term="Walkability"></category><category term="Community"></category><category term="Art"></category><category term="Home Zones"></category></entry><entry><title>Fall Into This Month's Community Events</title><link href="https://lovelicton.com/september-events-2018.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-09-01T17:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-09-01T17:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>amandacrosley</name></author><id>tag:lovelicton.com,2018-09-01:/september-events-2018.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Wow! Summer flew by but not to worry, we have some great community events happening this month before it's time for rain jackets, corn mazes, and pumpkin spice lattes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Social Events&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Saturday, September 8th @ 11AM-5PM, &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/2043515432535184/"&gt;Thai Festival&lt;/a&gt;, North Seattle College
&lt;a href="/images/events/2018/september/thai.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Thai Festival!" src="/images/events/2018/september/thai.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Saturday, September 15th @1PM- 3PM , &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/318018722104303/"&gt;Licton Springs P-Patch 5th Anniversary …&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Wow! Summer flew by but not to worry, we have some great community events happening this month before it's time for rain jackets, corn mazes, and pumpkin spice lattes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Social Events&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Saturday, September 8th @ 11AM-5PM, &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/2043515432535184/"&gt;Thai Festival&lt;/a&gt;, North Seattle College
&lt;a href="/images/events/2018/september/thai.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Thai Festival!" src="/images/events/2018/september/thai.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Saturday, September 15th @1PM- 3PM , &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/318018722104303/"&gt;Licton Springs P-Patch 5th Anniversary Potluck&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/events/2018/september/ppatch_party.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="P-Patch 5th Anniversary Party!" src="/images/events/2018/september/ppatch_party.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Saturday, September 15th @6PM-10PM, &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/2045140935551342/"&gt;Outdoor Movie &amp;amp; Dog Pawty&lt;/a&gt;, Mineral Springs Park
&lt;a href="/images/events/2018/september/dog_pawty.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Outdoor Movie and Dog Pawty!" src="/images/events/2018/september/dog_pawty.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tuesday, September 18th @6:30PM-8PM, &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1749802818460952/"&gt;Learn to Disc Golf,&lt;/a&gt; Mineral Springs Park
&lt;a href="/images/events/2018/september/disc_golf.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Free Begineers Disc Golf!" src="/images/events/2018/september/disc_golf.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Community Events&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wednesday, September 5th @ 9:30AM, &lt;a href="https://lovelicton.com/the-time-to-rezone-aurora-is-now.html"&gt;Public hearing on the ALUV moratorium extension&lt;/a&gt; @ Council Chambers at City Hall&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Saturday, September 8th @ 10AM-2PM, &lt;a href="https://lictonsprings.org/work_party.pdf"&gt;Friends of Licton Springs Park Clean Up&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tuesday, September 11th @ 6PM-7PM, &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/208110006726182/"&gt;Mineral Springs Park Community Meeting&lt;/a&gt;, Meridian Health Center, room 110&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thursday, September 13th @ 6:30PM, &lt;a href="https://lovelicton.com/home-zone-2018.html"&gt;Licton Springs Home Zone Pilot&lt;/a&gt;, Meridian Health Center&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thursday, September 13th @ 7PM, &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/274976659772168/"&gt;ALUV Monthly Community Meeting&lt;/a&gt;, Epic Life Church&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wednesday, September 19th @6:30PM-8PM, &lt;a href="https://lictonsprings.org/"&gt;Licton Springs Community Council&lt;/a&gt;, Meridian Center for Health&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thursday, September 20th @5-7PM, &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/664767133904232/"&gt;Mineral Springs Work Party&lt;/a&gt;, Mineral Springs Park South Entrance. A work party to clean and maintain the Mineral Springs Park. Sponsored by Seattle Parks &amp;amp; Recreation, Randy Wiger. Tools, gloves, and a snack are provided.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are lots of ways to connect with your neighbors. To stay up to date, check out LoveLicton's &lt;a href="https://lovelicton.com/pages/community-calendar.html"&gt;calendar&lt;/a&gt;!  Hope to see you there!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Did we miss an event? Let us know in the comments below!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="General"></category><category term="Community Meeting"></category><category term="Event"></category><category term="Outdoors"></category><category term="Parks"></category></entry><entry><title>Opinion: We need your help to extend the push for Aurora revitalization</title><link href="https://lovelicton.com/aurora-zone-controls-extension-2018.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-08-31T20:25:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-08-31T20:25:00-07:00</updated><author><name>timothycrosley</name></author><id>tag:lovelicton.com,2018-08-31:/aurora-zone-controls-extension-2018.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Call to Action:&lt;/strong&gt; We hope you will &lt;a href="http://auroralictonuv.org/2018/08/28/interim-controls-extension/"&gt;work with ALUV to extend the Aurora zoning controls&lt;/a&gt; and help ensure a vibrant Aurora Village has a chance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, I recently had to &lt;a href="https://lovelicton.com/original_north_seattle_starbucks_closing.html"&gt;report on the upcoming closure of the Oak Tree Starbucks&lt;/a&gt;, the only Coffee Shop within the Aurora Licton Urban …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Call to Action:&lt;/strong&gt; We hope you will &lt;a href="http://auroralictonuv.org/2018/08/28/interim-controls-extension/"&gt;work with ALUV to extend the Aurora zoning controls&lt;/a&gt; and help ensure a vibrant Aurora Village has a chance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, I recently had to &lt;a href="https://lovelicton.com/original_north_seattle_starbucks_closing.html"&gt;report on the upcoming closure of the Oak Tree Starbucks&lt;/a&gt;, the only Coffee Shop within the Aurora Licton Urban Village (ALUV). This came not too long after the nearby Gold's Gym, which brought additional caffeine craving foot traffic to the area, closed to be replaced by a storage facility. This facility &lt;a href="https://lovelicton.com/golds-gym-hearing.html"&gt;did have an appeal put forth&lt;/a&gt;, but it was dropped before being heard. This is one of 2 large storage facilities being built in the area. And while some storage is undoubtedly necessary, it is sad to see so much land taken off the market. Property that could instead be used for much needed additional housing which would support a thriving retail core within ALUV. As it is, the village is set to contain at least four storage facilities and not a single coffee shop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://lovelicton.com/golds-gym-hearing.html"&gt;&lt;img alt="Gold's Gym becomes Public Storage." src="/images/golds_gym/public_storage.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only thing that has kept even more of the land along Aurora from being repurposed for storage use is a temporary moratorium that was put in place October 2017, right after these storage facilities applied for permits. When this moratorium was passed, the intention was that it would act as a stop-gap measure until permanent zoning changes took effect with the passage of HALA. Predictably though, that law has been delayed by legal challenges, leaving the moratorium set to expire soon with no zoning changes in place. On Wednesday, Sept. 5th at 9:30 AM the Seattle City Council Planning, Land Use and Zoning (PLUZ) Committee will hold a public hearing on the renewal of the Interim Zoning Controls for the Aurora Licton Residential Urban Village. We hope to encourage you to &lt;a href="http://auroralictonuv.org/2018/08/28/interim-controls-extension/"&gt;come out in support of the extension and/or email the Seattle City Council&lt;/a&gt; with your thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to make it clear: this is not an attack on the many existing businesses along Aurora that may fall into the categories being blocked by this extension. Many of them are family run, have been here for decades, and have always done their best to help the community. We are glad they are here, appreciate their contributions, and hope they continue to thrive. This zoning extension and the permanent zoning changes proposed will not affect existing businesses or already pending permits. The goal is only to encourage more housing, and pedestrian-friendly businesses are built in existing empty lots and new lots as they become available. We believe this will result in a more lively and friendly area that will benefit both residents and existing businesses alike.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Call to Action:&lt;/strong&gt; We hope you will &lt;a href="http://auroralictonuv.org/2018/08/28/interim-controls-extension/"&gt;work with ALUV to extend the Aurora zoning controls&lt;/a&gt; and help ensure a vibrant Aurora Village has a chance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;</content><category term="General"></category><category term="Zoning"></category><category term="Pedestrian"></category><category term="Business"></category></entry><entry><title>Starbucks's Original North Seattle Store is Closing</title><link href="https://lovelicton.com/original_north_seattle_starbucks_closing.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-08-20T20:25:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-08-20T20:25:00-07:00</updated><author><name>timothycrosley</name></author><id>tag:lovelicton.com,2018-08-20:/original_north_seattle_starbucks_closing.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;It's a sad day for Starbucks lovers in Licton Springs.
After 31 years the Oak Tree Starbucks location is set to close permanently this September.
The location was Starbuck's first to open in North Seattle and one of the 10 original stores.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/oaktree/starbucks.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Starbuck's Last Month" src="/images/oaktree/starbucks.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regulars, some of who have been going to …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It's a sad day for Starbucks lovers in Licton Springs.
After 31 years the Oak Tree Starbucks location is set to close permanently this September.
The location was Starbuck's first to open in North Seattle and one of the 10 original stores.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/oaktree/starbucks.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Starbuck's Last Month" src="/images/oaktree/starbucks.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regulars, some of who have been going to the store since it first opened, have been given the news they will soon need to get their caffeine fix elsewhere. A hard pill to swallow, without a single coffee shop available within a 15 Minute Walk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The closure will add to the many other empty storefronts at the plaza:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/oaktree/closing_1.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Store Closures" src="/images/oaktree/closing_1.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/oaktree/closing_2.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Store Closures" src="/images/oaktree/closing_2.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/oaktree/closing_3.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Store Closures" src="/images/oaktree/closing_3.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many of which closed after the complex lost Larry’s Markets and with it significant foot traffic.
And while the complex has recently had a bit of a revitalization in the last year, with the remodeled AMC bringing in a substantial increase in customers, the Starbuck's 6 PM closing schedule may not have effectively leveraged the bulk of the additional movie traffic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of the day, while many things may have contributed to the closure:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Many new Starbucks opening nearby. Including one on N 84TH that is more easily accessible for pass-through traffic w/ a drive-through.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Few evening hours.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A growing preference to frequent small independent coffee stores, even if that means drinking coffee near where you work instead of where you live.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The store is closing for the reason most business closures happen: it is not profitable.
While many will be sad to see it go, we can only hope it leads to a small independent coffee shop finally opening in Licton Springs -
just like the Starbucks itself was when it opened in the area so many years ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you'd like to contact Starbuck's Corporate about the closure, you can use &lt;a href="https://customerservice.starbucks.com/app/contact/ask_company_info/"&gt;this form&lt;/a&gt; to do so.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="General"></category><category term="Retail"></category><category term="Coffee"></category><category term="Business Closure"></category></entry><entry><title>North Seattle Picnics in the Precincts is This Saturday!</title><link href="https://lovelicton.com/precinct-picnic-2018.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-08-15T20:25:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-08-15T20:25:00-07:00</updated><author><name>amandacrosley</name></author><id>tag:lovelicton.com,2018-08-15:/precinct-picnic-2018.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/2018_precinct_picnic/flyer.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Flyer" src="/images/2018_precinct_picnic/flyer.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Did you know the only Police Station in all of North Seattle is right here in Licton Springs? Now is your chance to meet them! This Saturday, August 18th from 1 pm to 4 pm at the Seattle Police Dept-North Precinct (10049 College Way N) the police department will be …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/2018_precinct_picnic/flyer.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Flyer" src="/images/2018_precinct_picnic/flyer.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Did you know the only Police Station in all of North Seattle is right here in Licton Springs? Now is your chance to meet them! This Saturday, August 18th from 1 pm to 4 pm at the Seattle Police Dept-North Precinct (10049 College Way N) the police department will be hosting a picnic. Come check out various booths (including LoveLicton.com!), enjoy music and meet with the many Department units including K-9, Mounted Patrol, Bomb Squad, and SWAT. Precinct Picnics provide opportunities for each precinct’s surrounding neighborhoods to come together and enjoy an afternoon of celebration with the officers that protect their families and businesses. Businesses financially support the event through donations and community groups assist in the planning and execution of each picnic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some images from last years picnic:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/2017_precinct_picnic/vehicles.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Precinct Vehicles" src="/images/2017_precinct_picnic/vehicles.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/2017_precinct_picnic/horses.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Horses!" src="/images/2017_precinct_picnic/horses.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/2017_precinct_picnic/horses_2.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="More Horses!" src="/images/2017_precinct_picnic/horses_2.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/2017_precinct_picnic/tents.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Tents" src="/images/2017_precinct_picnic/tents.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/2017_precinct_picnic/at_attention.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Dog At Attention" src="/images/2017_precinct_picnic/at_attention.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/2017_precinct_picnic/robot_lolipops.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Robot Delivering Lolipops!" src="/images/2017_precinct_picnic/robot_lolipops.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/2017_precinct_picnic/softserve.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Soft-serve!" src="/images/2017_precinct_picnic/softserve.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/2017_precinct_picnic/band.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Live music" src="/images/2017_precinct_picnic/band.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(See all images &lt;a href="http://www.seattlepolicefoundation.org/events/precinct-picnics-photos/north-precinct-picnic-2017"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information about the event, please see &lt;a href="http://www.seattlepolicefoundation.org/events/precinct-picnics"&gt;the Police Department's website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For sponsorship information, please contact &lt;a href="mailto:Justin@seattlepolicefoundation.org"&gt;Justin@seattlepolicefoundation.org&lt;/a&gt; or 206-733-9372.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To register for a booth at the picnics, please contact &lt;a href="mailto:Diane.Pilon@seattle.gov"&gt;Diane.Pilon@seattle.gov&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hope to see you there!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/H_or8biB1K4" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; encrypted-media" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</content><category term="General"></category><category term="Activities"></category><category term="Picnic"></category><category term="Community"></category><category term="Police"></category></entry><entry><title>Licton Springs chosen for Home Zone pilot</title><link href="https://lovelicton.com/home-zone-2018.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-08-12T04:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-08-12T04:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>timothycrosley</name></author><id>tag:lovelicton.com,2018-08-12:/home-zone-2018.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;We're excited to announce that Seattle Neighborhood Greenways has selected the southeastern corner of Licton Springs for its pioneering home zone pilot in North Seattle! Home Zones represent an innovative and inexpensive approach to increasing walkability, safety, and the sense of community in neighborhoods that lack full sidewalk coverage. The …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We're excited to announce that Seattle Neighborhood Greenways has selected the southeastern corner of Licton Springs for its pioneering home zone pilot in North Seattle! Home Zones represent an innovative and inexpensive approach to increasing walkability, safety, and the sense of community in neighborhoods that lack full sidewalk coverage. The pilot will cover the area north of 85TH, south of 92ND, west of I5 and east of Wallingford Ave. N Below is a map of the area, as well as some of the ideas that have already been proposed for the pilot:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src="https://www.google.com/maps/d/u/0/embed?mid=1D2yvYJGKPqQ2Sl-n9U1dxqXP5VucpecC" width="640" height="480"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This area was chosen, in particular, because it represents a small well-defined area in which to prove out the concept. If the pilot is successful: it could be expanded both to other areas in Licton Springs and throughout greater North Seattle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why are home zones something to get excited about?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is known by many that Seattle has a sidewalk, or rather lack thereof, problem.
As shown in this map prepared by SDOT in 2015, over a quarter of Seattle is laking sidewalk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/homezone/sidewalk_coverage.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Sidewalk Coverage" src="/images/homezone/sidewalk_coverage.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the need is concentrated in North Seattle, predominantly north of N 85th. And while Licton Springs is lucky to have the best sidewalk coverage of any neighborhood this far North, it still has less sidewalk coverage than any of the communities immediately to the south of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's an often repeated claim that Seattle promised all these areas sidewalk when they were annexed so many decades ago. And, while I haven't definitively been able to determine if &lt;a href="https://www.seattlepi.com/local/transportation/article/Getting-There-Did-the-city-promise-sidewalks-to-886368.php"&gt;that claim is fact or folklore&lt;/a&gt;, the city is &lt;a href="https://www.seattle.gov/transportation/projects-and-programs/programs/pedestrian-program/sidewalk-development-program"&gt;slowly keeping that promise&lt;/a&gt;. The only problem: starting at around $500K+ per a single block, sidewalks are expensive. At the current rate of expenditure, it will take over 300 years for all of Seattle to have sidewalks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are Home Zones and how do they aim to solve this problem?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Home Zone is an area that is protected from lots of fast moving traffic so that streets are safe enough to walk on. Home Zones keep local access for residents, emergency access, and deliveries while discouraging cut-through traffic. Home Zones can use a variety of street improvements to accomplish this but focus on improvements that have the best “bang for our buck” recognizing Seattle’s pedestrian budget is stretched very thin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Home Zones are meant to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make it safe and comfortable for people of all ages and abilities to walk in a neighborhood&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reduce cut-through traffic and speeding by keeping this traffic on the arterials (not increasing traffic on other neighborhood streets), while allowing neighbors to get to their homes, emergency access, deliveries, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enhance the quality of life for neighbors and strengthen our community (one way to do this is by integrating community art).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In essence: Home Zones aim to offer a drastically less expensive alternative to improve the walkability of currently unsidewalked streets, while also achieving a greater and more cohesive sense of community than can be made with sidewalks alone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Can I donate to the effort?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seattle Neighborhood Greenways which is a local nonprofit working to make every neighborhood a great place to walk, bike, and live, is currently supporting this project with staff time and resources. You can donate to help make this a reality at &lt;a href="http://seattlegreenways.org/"&gt;seattlegreenways.org&lt;/a&gt;. Or contact &lt;a href="mailto:Gordon@seattlegreenways.org"&gt;Gordon@seattlegreenways.org&lt;/a&gt; for more information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What happens next? How can I get involved?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you live in or near the pilot area or want to give input on the very first North Seattle home zone, you can find more information about the details of this project &lt;a href="https://lovelicton.com/pages/homezone"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.
Additionally, we encourage you to &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLScAtYcX8J4IQE_agDKW45oXHEvzt0LaOTQ1lImnO8CdkqSScg/viewform?usp=pp_url&amp;amp;entry.1991292058=Yes"&gt;fill out the survey here&lt;/a&gt;
or email us at &lt;a href="mailto:meridianhomezone@gmail.com"&gt;meridianhomezone@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt; to be kept up to date on the project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first public in-person meeting to provide feedback will be held at the Meridian Health Center (10521 Meridian Ave) starting at 6:30 PM September 13th.
If able, please register your intention to attend the meeting on &lt;a href="http://seattlegreenways.org/homezone/"&gt;Seattle Greenways home zone website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We hope to see you there!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="General"></category><category term="Pedestrian"></category><category term="Walkability"></category><category term="Community"></category><category term="Art"></category><category term="Home Zones"></category></entry><entry><title>Night Out Success!</title><link href="https://lovelicton.com/night-out-2018-success.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-08-11T01:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-08-11T01:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>timothycrosley</name></author><id>tag:lovelicton.com,2018-08-11:/night-out-2018-success.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Thank you to everyone that came out across Licton Springs to meet with your neighbors and make 2018 another great success! Across the Licton Springs area, hundreds of neighbors got to know each other across over seven block parties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/2018_night_out/packed.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Packed!" src="/images/2018_night_out/packed.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/2018_night_out/packed_2.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Packed!" src="/images/2018_night_out/packed_2.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/2018_night_out/bubble_man.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Bubble Man" src="/images/2018_night_out/bubble_man.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/2018_night_out/community_board.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Community Board" src="/images/2018_night_out/community_board.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/2018_night_out/be_prepared.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Emergency Preperation Board" src="/images/2018_night_out/be_prepared.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many community resources were shared at these block parties, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.smart911.com/"&gt;Smart …&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Thank you to everyone that came out across Licton Springs to meet with your neighbors and make 2018 another great success! Across the Licton Springs area, hundreds of neighbors got to know each other across over seven block parties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/2018_night_out/packed.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Packed!" src="/images/2018_night_out/packed.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/2018_night_out/packed_2.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Packed!" src="/images/2018_night_out/packed_2.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/2018_night_out/bubble_man.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Bubble Man" src="/images/2018_night_out/bubble_man.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/2018_night_out/community_board.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Community Board" src="/images/2018_night_out/community_board.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/2018_night_out/be_prepared.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Emergency Preperation Board" src="/images/2018_night_out/be_prepared.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many community resources were shared at these block parties, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.smart911.com/"&gt;Smart 911&lt;/a&gt; - A way to add the information you want responders to know in case of an emergency before one happens.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://alert.seattle.gov/"&gt;Alert Seattle&lt;/a&gt; - The official emergency notification system used by the City of Seattle to communicate with city residents during emergencies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.seattle.gov/police/community-policing/block-watch"&gt;Block Watch&lt;/a&gt; - Instructions on how to start an officially recognized neighborhood block watch.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.seattle.gov/emergency-management/about-us/event-calendar/"&gt;Emergency Event Calendar&lt;/a&gt; - Upcoming events that teach crucial skills needed in the case of an emergency.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.seattle.gov/emergency-management/prepare/prepare-your-neighborhood/community-emergency-hubs"&gt;Emergency Hubs&lt;/a&gt; - A map of all the nearby emergency hubs to meet at after an emergency strikes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://lovelicton.com/pages/community-calendar.html"&gt;Licton Springs Community Calendar&lt;/a&gt; - A shared calendar for all the events happening across the Licton Springs area.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's to hoping the community connections made at Night Out continue to grow over the next year!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="General"></category><category term="Event"></category><category term="Outdoors"></category><category term="Parks"></category><category term="Community"></category></entry><entry><title>Night Out is TODAY!</title><link href="https://lovelicton.com/night-out-2018.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-08-07T01:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-08-07T01:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>timothycrosley</name></author><id>tag:lovelicton.com,2018-08-07:/night-out-2018.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Reminder: TONIGHT all across Licton Springs and Seattle is Night Out! Come together with your neighbors for good food, activities, and conversation!
Below is a map of all the publically listed night outs in the Licton Springs area:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src="https://www.google.com/maps/d/u/0/embed?mid=11lWvVcrL4vlWz2JhBD007f5Fl76V0Dh9" width="640" height="480"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your direct area isn't getting together, the Densmore Block Watch Barbecue …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Reminder: TONIGHT all across Licton Springs and Seattle is Night Out! Come together with your neighbors for good food, activities, and conversation!
Below is a map of all the publically listed night outs in the Licton Springs area:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src="https://www.google.com/maps/d/u/0/embed?mid=11lWvVcrL4vlWz2JhBD007f5Fl76V0Dh9" width="640" height="480"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your direct area isn't getting together, the Densmore Block Watch Barbecue is open to the entire neighborhood and is holding its night out at Licton Spring Park.
&lt;a href="/images/densmore_night_out.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Densmore Block Watch Barbecue" src="/images/densmore_night_out.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.seattle.gov/police/community-policing/night-out/view-the-map"&gt;Click here for a map of all the Night Out celebrations being held accross Seattle.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Did we miss your Night Out celebration? Let us know in a comment below!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="General"></category><category term="Event"></category><category term="Outdoors"></category><category term="Parks"></category><category term="Community"></category></entry><entry><title>Mineral Springs Park is Bringing Community Together</title><link href="https://lovelicton.com/mineral-springs-coming-to-life.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-08-01T01:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-08-01T01:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>amandacrosley</name></author><id>tag:lovelicton.com,2018-08-01:/mineral-springs-coming-to-life.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Mineral Springs park has had a busy and successful month! See below for a summary of July's events and some ways to get involved this month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Community Connection:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On July 3rd, the community around Mineral Springs park met to discuss future events and initiatives in the park. If you'd like …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Mineral Springs park has had a busy and successful month! See below for a summary of July's events and some ways to get involved this month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Community Connection:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On July 3rd, the community around Mineral Springs park met to discuss future events and initiatives in the park. If you'd like to get involved, the next Seattle Parks community meeting will be held on &lt;strong&gt;Tuesday, August 14th from 6-7pm at Meridian Center for Health, room 110&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Disc Golf:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Did you know that the Mineral Springs Park is the only disc golf course in the city of Seattle? On July 12th, Seattle Parks department met with the disc golf community to discuss needed improvements to the disc golf course in Mineral Springs Park. Additionally, on July 17th, LoveLicton.com held its second "Learn to Disc Golf" event in partnership with the local disc golfers. The event was a resounding success! We will be holding our next beginner's disc golf event on &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1749802818460952/"&gt;Tuesday, August 21st from 6:30pm to 8pm&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/mineral_springs/beginners_disc_golf.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Beginner's Disc Golf" src="/images/mineral_springs/beginners_disc_golf.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1749802818460952/"&gt;&lt;img alt="Beginner's Disc Golf Event Flyer" src="/images/mineral_springs/discgolfflyer.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Clean up:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On July 19th, the community came together for a Mineral Springs Park work party to help increase visibility in the park and clear tremendous amounts of brush and blackberries, primarily from the southeast corner along the walkway. You can really see the difference!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/mineral_springs/park_cleanup.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Neighborhood comes together to clean up" src="/images/mineral_springs/park_cleanup.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/mineral_springs/park_cleanup_2.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Neighborhood comes together to clean up" src="/images/mineral_springs/park_cleanup_2.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/mineral_springs/park_cleanup_3.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Neighborhood comes together to clean up" src="/images/mineral_springs/park_cleanup_3.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the next cleanup will be held on &lt;strong&gt;Thursday, August 16th from 5-7pm&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Celebrate:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On July 21st, the community, in partnership with Seattle Parks, held their first event - a free BBQ! Lawn games, live music, food, and neighborhood bonding! Lots of fun was had by all.  Thanks to &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/howshortjazz/"&gt;How Short&lt;/a&gt; for keeping us entertained with live jazz and our neighborhood volunteers who tended to the grills! Look out for our next event later this summer/early fall.
&lt;a href="/images/mineral_springs/bbq_summary.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="BBQ" src="/images/mineral_springs/bbq_summary.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's been amazing meeting so many wonderful people from the area and seeing the community come together around this Licton Spring's gem.
Let's keep up the community engagement! Hope to see you at some of the upcoming events.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/mineral_springs/august.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="August Events" src="/images/mineral_springs/august.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="General"></category><category term="Community Meeting"></category><category term="Event"></category><category term="Outdoors"></category><category term="Parks"></category></entry><entry><title>More frequent bus service coming soon near you</title><link href="https://lovelicton.com/more-frequent-bus-service-2018.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-07-25T20:15:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-07-25T20:15:00-07:00</updated><author><name>timothycrosley</name></author><id>tag:lovelicton.com,2018-07-25:/more-frequent-bus-service-2018.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.kingcounty.gov/elected/executive/constantine/news/release/2018/July/25-metro-service-amazon-seattle.aspx"&gt;Starting this September the frequency of the E Line, in addition to many other regional bus lines, will be increased&lt;/a&gt;. This change is happening thanks to a partnership between Amazon, the City of Seattle, and King County Metro. This will be a particularly welcome addition over the next few years …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.kingcounty.gov/elected/executive/constantine/news/release/2018/July/25-metro-service-amazon-seattle.aspx"&gt;Starting this September the frequency of the E Line, in addition to many other regional bus lines, will be increased&lt;/a&gt;. This change is happening thanks to a partnership between Amazon, the City of Seattle, and King County Metro. This will be a particularly welcome addition over the next few years as the &lt;a href="https://komonews.com/news/local/metros-convention-place-station-closing-saturday-for-good"&gt;recent closure of the Convention Place Station&lt;/a&gt; reroutes our other popular bus line into downtown: the 41 - leading to possible delays until the light rail construction is complete.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/aurora/more_frequent.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="More Frequent E Line Service" src="/images/aurora/more_frequent.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This change will positively affect many as the E Line is Metro’s highest-ridership route with more than 17,000 weekday riders.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="General"></category><category term="Transportation"></category><category term="Bus"></category></entry><entry><title>WE'RE NUMBER 1!?</title><link href="https://lovelicton.com/most-competitive-neighborhood.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-07-24T20:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-07-24T20:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>timothycrosley</name></author><id>tag:lovelicton.com,2018-07-24:/most-competitive-neighborhood.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Whether you call it Licton Springs, North Green Lake, North College Park, or that magical portal in-between Green Lake, Greenwood, and the Northgate mall - we are all proud to call it home. And, apparently, according to a new report from Redfin, we are not the only ones who would like …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Whether you call it Licton Springs, North Green Lake, North College Park, or that magical portal in-between Green Lake, Greenwood, and the Northgate mall - we are all proud to call it home. And, apparently, according to a new report from Redfin, we are not the only ones who would like to do so. Licton Springs showed up on &lt;a href="https://www.geekwire.com/2018/redfins-new-compete-score-ranks-markets-based-competition-homes-seattle-toughest/"&gt;Redfin's report&lt;/a&gt; as the #1 most competitive neighborhood to buy into, in not only Seattle, but the entire United States.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.geekwire.com/2018/redfins-new-compete-score-ranks-markets-based-competition-homes-seattle-toughest/"&gt;&lt;img alt="Redfin graphic" src="/images/most_competitive_neighborhood_2018.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We tied with ourselves (under the name North College Park, yep we are in the report twice) and 5 other neighborhoods including nearby Phinney Ridge for the spot. Having also received a property taxable value reassessment notice today, I'm not entirely sure it's a placement any of us were looking to achieve...&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="General"></category><category term="Neighborhood"></category><category term="Real Estate"></category></entry><entry><title>North Seattle Greenway Construction</title><link href="https://lovelicton.com/north-seattle-greenway-2018.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-07-22T23:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-07-22T23:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>timothycrosley</name></author><id>tag:lovelicton.com,2018-07-22:/north-seattle-greenway-2018.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A friend of the blog wrote in to let us know the construction of the North Seattle Neighborhood Greenway project down 100th Ave N is set to begin as soon as tomorrow.
The project aims to connect Crown Hill, Greenwood, and Licton Springs both to each other and to the …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A friend of the blog wrote in to let us know the construction of the North Seattle Neighborhood Greenway project down 100th Ave N is set to begin as soon as tomorrow.
The project aims to connect Crown Hill, Greenwood, and Licton Springs both to each other and to the upcoming pedestrian bridge that will provide direct access to the Northgate light rail station. While the entire project, which will stretch around 2 miles, is a welcome addition - of particular interest to those in the Licton Springs area are a &lt;a href="https://www.seattle.gov/Documents/Departments/SDOT/Greenways/N100thStFactsheet.pdf"&gt;new sidewalk from Linden Ave N to Aurora Ave N&lt;/a&gt; and sidewalk improvements being made between Aurora Ave N and Stone Ave N.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="images/2018_greenway/banner.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Linden currently without sidewalk" src="images/2018_greenway/banner.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="images/2018_greenway/linden_sidewalk.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Linden sidewalk area" src="images/2018_greenway/linden_sidewalk.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="images/2018_greenway/greenway_area.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="100th in Licton Springs" src="images/2018_greenway/greenway_area.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the work is complete, the hope is that it will be possible to safely walk or ride a bicycle all the way from Crown Hill to the new light rail station, with sidewalk at a  minimum from Linden Ave N eastward. You can find more information about the project on &lt;a href="https://www.seattle.gov/transportation/projects-and-programs/programs/greenways-program/north-seattle"&gt;SDOT's overview page&lt;/a&gt;. The project should take around 6 months to complete with individual neighbors being directly contacted as construction work that impacts them is underway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, the traffic circle on Wallingford Ave N and N 97th &lt;a href="https://lovelicton.com/street_improvements_preview_2018.html"&gt;we wrote about earlier this year&lt;/a&gt; has now been completed and is just awaiting greenery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="images/2018_greenway/circle.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Wallingford Ave N Circle" src="images/2018_greenway/circle.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We look forward to a safer and more walkable North Seattle!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="General"></category><category term="Construction"></category><category term="Pedestrian"></category><category term="Northgate"></category><category term="Greenwood"></category><category term="Crown Hill"></category></entry><entry><title>Appeal hearing set for property of old Gold's Gym</title><link href="https://lovelicton.com/golds-gym-hearing.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-07-21T17:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-07-21T17:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>timothycrosley</name></author><id>tag:lovelicton.com,2018-07-21:/golds-gym-hearing.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A member of the community has come forth to formally appeal the development of the old Gold's Gym location, which helped compliment other nearby business such as Emerald City Smoothie, into a storage facility. The area in question has a moratorium on non-pedestrian oriented businesses, but the permit for the …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A member of the community has come forth to formally appeal the development of the old Gold's Gym location, which helped compliment other nearby business such as Emerald City Smoothie, into a storage facility. The area in question has a moratorium on non-pedestrian oriented businesses, but the permit for the storage facility was placed right before it was put into effect. Beyond Aurora, the property is surrounded by homes and townhouses, and there is a strong desire by many within the area to increase housing and retail along Aurora, by lining it with apartment complexes that contain retail on the bottom. The thought being, that this would increase the safety of Aurora while helping to soften our current housing crises.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/golds_gym/location.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Gold's Gym Location" src="/images/golds_gym/location.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/golds_gym/public_storage.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Public Storage" src="/images/golds_gym/public_storage.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/golds_gym/land_use.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Notice of Land Use" src="/images/golds_gym/land_use.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/golds_gym/houses_behind_gym.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Houses behind gym" src="/images/golds_gym/houses_behind_gym.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The appeal comes as "Greenlake" Self-storage continues its construction just a few blocks south.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/golds_gym/greenlake.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Greenlake Self-Storage" src="/images/golds_gym/greenlake.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hearing for the appeal is set for 9 AM on Monday, Aug. 13, at the City of Seattle Hearing Examiner’s Office, Seattle Municipal Tower, 700 5th Ave., 40th Floor. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hearings are open to the public, but generally only those who are parties to the appeal and persons called by the parties as witnesses will have the opportunity to testify. A person who has not appealed, but who has a substantial interest in the outcome of the appeal, may request to be allowed to participate in an appeal as an “intervenor”. An intervenor, like the parties, would have the option of appealing the Hearing Examiner’s decision in this matter. Intervenor status should be requested as soon as possible prior to hearing and in accordance with the Hearing Examiner Rules. For information regarding appeals and intervenor status, contact or visit the Hearing Examiner. The Hearing Examiner’s office provides barrier-free access.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reason for the appeal reflects the concerns shared by many:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My interest is to maintain some sense of residential and environmental
neighborhood atmosphere. This project unfortunately has been grandfathered into the rezoning of
past. The current rezoning would not support this project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can see the full reasoning behind the appeal as well as all supporting documents on &lt;a href="https://web6.seattle.gov/Examiner/case/MUP-18-015"&gt;Seattle's Hearing Examiner site&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="General"></category><category term="Construction"></category><category term="Pedestrian"></category><category term="Aurora"></category></entry><entry><title>Downtown Northgate and our bridge to it continues to take shape</title><link href="https://lovelicton.com/downtown-northgate-taking-shape.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-07-15T15:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-07-15T15:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>timothycrosley</name></author><id>tag:lovelicton.com,2018-07-15:/downtown-northgate-taking-shape.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;For many years Northgate enjoyed the convenience of having both of the big name wine and beer outlets right next to each other.
Being able to easily walk between BevMo! and Total Wine in the same trip was a magical thing for anyone who anxiously awaited limited availability beer, wine …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;For many years Northgate enjoyed the convenience of having both of the big name wine and beer outlets right next to each other.
Being able to easily walk between BevMo! and Total Wine in the same trip was a magical thing for anyone who anxiously awaited limited availability beer, wine, or spirit releases.
Of course, one-day several months ago, this duo came to an end, leaving only Total Wine - which sits at the bottom of an apartment complex, left in-tact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A friend of the blog recently reached out to us, with an unsurprising explanation for that closure: BevMo!, which was nestled into an old-fashioned shopping strip, needed to close to make way for the expansion of Downtown Northgate. In the place of the old shopping plaza, plans are in place to build a 235 unit apartment building with retail at the bottom, continuing the trend happening around the old plaza:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/downtown_northgate/bevmo.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Old BevMo! Location" src="/images/downtown_northgate/bevmo.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/downtown_northgate/crane.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Construction Around the Building" src="/images/downtown_northgate/crane.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/downtown_northgate/alley.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alleyway showing grouping of mid-rises" src="/images/downtown_northgate/alley.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you would like to give your input into the design of this new apartment building, there is an upcoming opportunity to contribute to the early design guidance &lt;a href="http://www.seattle.gov/DPD/aboutus/news/events/DesignReview/Detail/default.aspx?id=6936"&gt;August 6, 2018 6:30 pm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, the redevelopment of the mall into the focal point of this new downtown area continues being planned, with the first two opportunities for community input coming tentatively next month:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.seattle.gov/DPD/aboutus/news/events/DesignReview/Detail/default.aspx?id=6930"&gt;August 13, 2018 6:30 pm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.seattle.gov/DPD/aboutus/news/events/DesignReview/Detail/default.aspx?id=6931"&gt;August 27, 2018 6:30 pm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The transit-oriented development, temporarily paused, has come back in full swing with a new RFP based on free land from King County and an upzone to allow up to 24 story buildings &lt;a href="https://www.seattletimes.com/seattle-news/transportation/king-county-moves-to-allow-affordable-housing-at-future-northgate-light-rail-station/"&gt;promised by the end of this month&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And finally, concerns over future of the Northgate Pedestrian bridge which will connect Licton Springs directly to both the developing Light Rail and Downtown Northgate, have been alleviated after the &lt;a href="https://cascade.org/blog/2018/06/bridge-92-northgate-biking-and-walking-bridge-moving-forward"&gt;Seattle Colleges Board of Trustees conditionally agreed to give an easement to the new bridge&lt;/a&gt;. The latest plans for which, will have the new bridge/path only a &lt;a href="https://www.google.com/maps/dir/47.7015386,-122.3422173/47.7014736,-122.335324/@47.7008021,-122.3419329,16z/data=!4m2!4m1!3e2"&gt;~5-10 minute walk away from Oak Tree Plaza&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/downtown_northgate/bridge.png"&gt;&lt;img alt="New Bridge" src="/images/downtown_northgate/bridge.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No matter how you feel about the developments overall, hopefully, this all will lead to a North Seattle that feels more connected both to Downtown Seattle and to the neighborhoods contained within.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="General"></category><category term="Transportation"></category><category term="Pedestrian"></category><category term="Construction"></category></entry><entry><title>Upcoming Events in Mineral Springs Park</title><link href="https://lovelicton.com/mineral-springs-events-july-2018.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-07-08T01:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-07-08T01:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>amandacrosley</name></author><id>tag:lovelicton.com,2018-07-08:/mineral-springs-events-july-2018.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Do you want to get involved in the Licton Springs community? Over the next 2 weeks, there are plenty of opportunities to meet your neighbors while having fun and improving the Mineral Springs Park!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;July 12th: Meeting to Improve Disc Golf Course&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time:&lt;/strong&gt; 6-7pm&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Location:&lt;/strong&gt; Meridian Center for Health (10521 …&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Do you want to get involved in the Licton Springs community? Over the next 2 weeks, there are plenty of opportunities to meet your neighbors while having fun and improving the Mineral Springs Park!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;July 12th: Meeting to Improve Disc Golf Course&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time:&lt;/strong&gt; 6-7pm&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Location:&lt;/strong&gt; Meridian Center for Health (10521 Meridian Ave N, Seattle, WA 98133)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sponsor:&lt;/strong&gt; Randy Wiger, Seattle Parks &amp;amp; Recreation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/mineral_springs/improve_course.png"&gt;&lt;img alt="Disc Golf Course Improvement Meeting" src="/images/mineral_springs/improve_course.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
If you're a disc golfer make sure to put this meeting on your calendar!
Here you can provide feedback to the city on what repairs or improvements should be made to the Mineral Springs Disc Golf course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;July 17th: Learn To Disc Golf&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time:&lt;/strong&gt; 6:30pm to 8pm&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Location:&lt;/strong&gt; Mineral Springs Park (1500 N 105th St, Seattle, WA 98133)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Event URL:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/618053928556827"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/618053928556827&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sponsor:&lt;/strong&gt; LoveLicton&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/mineral_springs/learn.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Learn to Disc Golf!" src="/images/mineral_springs/learn.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
Do you want to learn to disc golf?
Come join us for a beginner's disc golf game at Mineral Springs Park with help from members of the local disc golf community. At this event, you will not only learn how to play alongside other beginners but will also be able to receive valuable tips from some more veteran disc golf players. All are welcome to this free event!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;July 19th: Mineral Springs Park Clean Up&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time:&lt;/strong&gt; 5-7pm&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Location:&lt;/strong&gt; Mineral Springs Park (1500 N 105th St, Seattle, WA 98133)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sponsor:&lt;/strong&gt; Randy Wiger, Seattle Parks &amp;amp; Recreation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/mineral_springs/clean.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Mineral Springs Park Clean Up" src="/images/mineral_springs/clean.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
Come join your neighbors at a Parks department-supported clean up event. Refreshments and tools will be provided.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;July 21st: Mineral Springs Park Community BBQ&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time:&lt;/strong&gt; 11am -1pm&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Location:&lt;/strong&gt; Mineral Springs Park (1500 N 105th St, Seattle, WA 98133)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Event URL:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/250408269069372/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/250408269069372/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sponsor:&lt;/strong&gt; Seattle Parks &amp;amp; Recreation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/mineral_springs/bbq.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Mineral Springs BBQ!" src="/images/mineral_springs/bbq.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
Come meet your neighbors for a free BBQ at Mineral Springs Park!
More details to be provided closer to the event but a little birdie told us that there will be music, hot dogs, and lawn games.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="General"></category><category term="Community Meeting"></category><category term="Event"></category><category term="Outdoors"></category><category term="Parks"></category></entry><entry><title>Teriyaki Taste Test!</title><link href="https://lovelicton.com/teriyaki-taste-test-2018.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-07-07T01:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-07-07T01:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>timothycrosley</name></author><id>tag:lovelicton.com,2018-07-07:/teriyaki-taste-test-2018.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In Seattle, we all LOVE good Teriyaki. Licton Springs is no exception, and we are lucky to have at least &lt;em&gt;4&lt;/em&gt; Teriyaki places within our &amp;lt; 1 square mile neighborhood.
With so many to choose from it can be difficult to know which one to try out. So, we decided to …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In Seattle, we all LOVE good Teriyaki. Licton Springs is no exception, and we are lucky to have at least &lt;em&gt;4&lt;/em&gt; Teriyaki places within our &amp;lt; 1 square mile neighborhood.
With so many to choose from it can be difficult to know which one to try out. So, we decided to make the only logical decision and try all 4!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;The methodology&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this taste test we decided to go with the plain Teriyaki Chicken dish from all 4 locations.
We took turns with a blindfold on while the other randomly gave us a taste of one of the Teriyaki dishes and asked for a score from 1-5.
We didn't include cost in our calculation since all 4 Teriyaki places had their Teriyaki priced within a few dimes of each other in the $8 range.
NOTE: Many of them also have lunch specials for around $7.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;The contenders&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/teriyaki/all.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="The spread" src="/images/teriyaki/all.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Manna Deli Teriyaki
    &lt;a href="/images/teriyaki/manna.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Manna Deli Teriyaki Store Front" src="/images/teriyaki/manna.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conveniently located on Aurora and with very friendly service, this Teriyaki place currently enjoys the highest rating of the 3 Teriyaki only restaurants on Yelp, but unfortunately had the lowest health rating at the time we went.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Address: 9831 Aurora Ave N Seattle, WA 98103&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hours: 11AM-9PM Monday-Saturday, Closed Sunday&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Current Health Rating: Okay&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oak Tree Teriyaki
    &lt;a href="/images/teriyaki/oaktree.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Oak Tree Teriyaki Store Front" src="/images/teriyaki/oaktree.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Located in the Oak Tree Plaza, right near the recently remodeled AMC (easily one of the comfiest theaters in Seattle now), this has long been my favorite Teriyaki place. The owner is super friendly,
they have these excellent house fries, and they have hours that work pretty well for eating before or after movies. However, I always get the Spicy Teriyaki here, so I'm curious to see how the regular Teriyaki fares.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Address: 10002 Aurora Ave N, Seattle, WA 98133&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hours: 11AM-9PM Monday-Saturday, Closed Sunday&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Current Health Rating: Good&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Teriyaki Plus
    &lt;a href="/images/teriyaki/plus.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Teriyaki Plus Store Front" src="/images/teriyaki/plus.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only Teriyaki place of the 4 that neither of us had been to before, so we are both stoked to try it out for the first time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Address: 2100 N Northgate Way b, Seattle, WA 98133&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hours: 11AM-9PM Monday-Saturday, Closed Sunday&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Current Health Rating: Excellent&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cafe Banh Mi
    &lt;a href="/images/teriyaki/banh.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Cafe Banh Mi Sign" src="/images/teriyaki/banh.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tucked away in a business complex on Meridian Ave, Cafe Banh Mi is the only place we tried that isn't marketed as a Teriyaki restaurant. It does, however, happen to have Teriyaki permanently on the menu. We discovered this when traveling back to Seattle on an early morning flight. We missed Seattle Teriyaki so much on our vacation - that we craved it upon returning. Cafe Banh Mi was the only place that served Teriyaki we could find that was also open at 8 AM. However, their matching early close time and non-existent weekend hours mean we don't get to enjoy this place nearly as often as we'd like to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Address: 10700 Meridian Ave N #106, Seattle, WA 98133&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hours: 7AM-5PM Monday-Friday, Closed Saturday &amp;amp; Sunday&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Current Health Rating: Excellent&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src="https://www.google.com/maps/d/u/0/embed?mid=19y6zsARIcndxmgFwdlQJm2rqrtxopuSo" width="640" height="480"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;The ratings&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cafe Banh Mi
    &lt;a href="/images/teriyaki/banh_teriyaki.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Cafe Banh Mi's Teriyaki" src="/images/teriyaki/banh_teriyaki.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With a generous coating of Teriyaki glaze covering perfectly moist chicken, Cafe Banh Mi easily took the #1 spot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Amanda: 4.5 - "Delicious. I want more."&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tim: 4.5 - "By far the best."&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oak Tree Teriyaki
    &lt;a href="/images/teriyaki/oaktree_teriyaki.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Oak Tree's Teriyaki" src="/images/teriyaki/oaktree_teriyaki.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    Oak Tree's distinctive crunch helped pull it into #2 place. And then there are those glorious house fries...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Amanda: 3.75&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tim 4.0 - "Has a really nice crunch to it."&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/teriyaki/oaktree_fries.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Oak Tree's Fries" src="/images/teriyaki/oaktree_fries.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
Bonus (House Fries):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Amanda: 5.0 - "This isn't what we are taste testing, but these are delicious."&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tim: 10 - "That's right, these are off the scale. It's a good thing these aren't included in the actual rating."&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Manna Deli Teriyaki
    &lt;a href="/images/teriyaki/manna_teriyaki.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Manna Deli Teriyaki" src="/images/teriyaki/manna_teriyaki.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Amanda: 3.5 - "Has a nice flavor to it, but I want a bit more."&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tim 3.25&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Teriyaki Plus
    &lt;a href="/images/teriyaki/plus_teriyaki.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Teriyaki Plus" src="/images/teriyaki/plus_teriyaki.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    Some more teriyaki sauce may have made all the difference for this one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Amanda: 3.25 - "Too Dry."&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tim 3.0 - "Too Dry!"&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Disagree with our ratings? Let us know why in the comments! Either way, go eat some delicious Teriyaki in Licton Springs!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="General"></category><category term="Restaurants"></category><category term="Business"></category></entry><entry><title>The Original Seattle Real Estate Gold Rush</title><link href="https://lovelicton.com/burke-pamphlet.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-07-03T20:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-07-03T20:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>timothycrosley</name></author><id>tag:lovelicton.com,2018-07-03:/burke-pamphlet.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A friend of the blog lent us a historical pamphlet from when Licton Springs was first being developed that I thought was too cool not to share.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/burke_pamphlet/banner.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Banner" src="/images/burke_pamphlet/banner.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/burke_pamphlet/cover.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Cover" src="/images/burke_pamphlet/cover.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/burke_pamphlet/reasons.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="24 Reasons" src="/images/burke_pamphlet/reasons.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/burke_pamphlet/licton_springs_park.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Park" src="/images/burke_pamphlet/licton_springs_park.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/burke_pamphlet/gardens.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Gardens" src="/images/burke_pamphlet/gardens.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/burke_pamphlet/water.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="New Water System" src="/images/burke_pamphlet/water.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/burke_pamphlet/close_in.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Close In" src="/images/burke_pamphlet/close_in.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/burke_pamphlet/city_of_homes.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="City of Homes" src="/images/burke_pamphlet/city_of_homes.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/burke_pamphlet/auto.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Auto" src="/images/burke_pamphlet/auto.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While many things have changed since this pamphlet initially went out, we still firmly believe that Licton Springs is a great neighborhood to …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A friend of the blog lent us a historical pamphlet from when Licton Springs was first being developed that I thought was too cool not to share.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/burke_pamphlet/banner.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Banner" src="/images/burke_pamphlet/banner.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/burke_pamphlet/cover.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Cover" src="/images/burke_pamphlet/cover.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/burke_pamphlet/reasons.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="24 Reasons" src="/images/burke_pamphlet/reasons.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/burke_pamphlet/licton_springs_park.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Park" src="/images/burke_pamphlet/licton_springs_park.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/burke_pamphlet/gardens.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Gardens" src="/images/burke_pamphlet/gardens.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/burke_pamphlet/water.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="New Water System" src="/images/burke_pamphlet/water.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/burke_pamphlet/close_in.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Close In" src="/images/burke_pamphlet/close_in.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/burke_pamphlet/city_of_homes.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="City of Homes" src="/images/burke_pamphlet/city_of_homes.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/burke_pamphlet/auto.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Auto" src="/images/burke_pamphlet/auto.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While many things have changed since this pamphlet initially went out, we still firmly believe that Licton Springs is a great neighborhood to join and be a part of.
Additionally, we still have &lt;a href="/an-early-preview-of-spring-in-licton-springs.html"&gt;Licton Springs Park&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="/licton-springs-ppatch-2018.html"&gt;Licton Springs Garden (reborn as a P-Patch)&lt;/a&gt;: as seen on our &lt;a href="/pages/map-of-the-neighborhood.html"&gt;Map of the Neighborhood&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let's keep investing in the future of Licton Springs!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="General"></category><category term="Historical"></category><category term="Burke"></category><category term="Neighborhood"></category><category term="Investment"></category></entry><entry><title>New Licton Springs Community Council website</title><link href="https://lovelicton.com/new-community-council-website.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-06-30T10:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-06-30T10:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>timothycrosley</name></author><id>tag:lovelicton.com,2018-06-30:/new-community-council-website.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://lictonsprings.org/"&gt;&lt;img alt="Website Partnership" src="/images/partnership.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the last month work has been going on behind the scenes to refresh the Licton Springs Community Council Website,
and I'm excited to say this new site is ready to be unveiled! You can now visit the brand new website at &lt;a href="https://lictonsprings.org"&gt;lictonsprings.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The community council has been the …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://lictonsprings.org/"&gt;&lt;img alt="Website Partnership" src="/images/partnership.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the last month work has been going on behind the scenes to refresh the Licton Springs Community Council Website,
and I'm excited to say this new site is ready to be unveiled! You can now visit the brand new website at &lt;a href="https://lictonsprings.org"&gt;lictonsprings.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The community council has been the force behind improving Licton Springs and giving everyone in the community a voice for more than two decades.
This new website is part of a broader push to introduce the council to a whole new generation so that their great work can include a
broader audience and have even more impact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have also added in our menu a permanent link directly to the community council and from the community council's website a permanent link to the blog.
As part of this partnership &lt;a href="https://lovelicton.com"&gt;lovelicton.com&lt;/a&gt; will continue to be the place to go to get a pulse on the community and read about the positive changes going on
and &lt;a href="https://lictonsprings.org"&gt;lictonsprings.org&lt;/a&gt; will be the place to join your neighbors and &lt;em&gt;make&lt;/em&gt; more of those positive changes happen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a reminder: the Licton Springs Community Council will have a booth at the &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1999117153465269/"&gt;Live in D5!&lt;/a&gt; event that is happening &lt;em&gt;today&lt;/em&gt; 1-4PM at Hubbart Homestead Park.
It's a great opportunity to get introduced to the council as well as many other nearby community groups - while enjoying:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3 local bands&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Free salmon and fry bread sponsored by the United Indians of All Tribes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A baby goat petting zoo&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><category term="General"></category><category term="Website"></category><category term="Licton Springs Community Council"></category><category term="Community Involvement"></category></entry><entry><title>Your Voice, Your Choice 2018: Licton Springs Park</title><link href="https://lovelicton.com/your-voice-your-choice-2018.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-06-22T08:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-06-22T08:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>amandacrosley</name></author><id>tag:lovelicton.com,2018-06-22:/your-voice-your-choice-2018.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h2&gt;It's time to VOTE for your favorite park and street improvements!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Voting for the 2018 Your Voice, Your Choice: Parks and Streets is now live and a proposal for improvements at Licton Springs Park (project 18-5001) is listed as one of the options for District 5! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As part of the …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;It's time to VOTE for your favorite park and street improvements!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Voting for the 2018 Your Voice, Your Choice: Parks and Streets is now live and a proposal for improvements at Licton Springs Park (project 18-5001) is listed as one of the options for District 5! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As part of the proposal, Seattle Parks and Recreation will repair the trails and bridges to make it easier for all people to move through Licton Springs Park and enjoy that natural area that is so close to where an increasing number of people are moving. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read more details about the proposed Licton Springs Park project &lt;a href="http://www.seattle.gov/Documents/Departments/Neighborhoods/ParticipatoryBudgeting/5K.%2018-5001%20Licton%20Springs%20Park.pdf"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To vote using your cell phone for confirmation, please register &lt;a href="https://pbstanford.org/seattle2018-d5/sms_signup"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or, you can go to one of the following places to cast your vote:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Northgate Branch Library- 10548 5th Ave NE, Seattle, WA 98125&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Broadview Branch Library- 12755 Greenwood Ave N, Seattle, WA 98133&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lake City Community Center (closed July 1-7)- 12531 28th Ave NE, Seattle, WA 98125&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Central Library- 1000 4th Ave, Seattle, WA 98104&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each voter may cast one ballot per City Council district, and may choose up to three (3) projects per district. Voting is open until &lt;strong&gt;July 16th&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find more information about Your Voice, Your Choice &lt;a href="http://www.seattle.gov/neighborhoods/programs-and-services/your-voice-your-choice/get-involved/vote"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="General"></category><category term="Parks"></category><category term="Improvements"></category><category term="Voting"></category></entry><entry><title>Come Learn how to Disc Golf!</title><link href="https://lovelicton.com/come-learn-disc-golf.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-06-10T08:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-06-10T08:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>timothycrosley</name></author><id>tag:lovelicton.com,2018-06-10:/come-learn-disc-golf.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Have you ever wanted to learn how to disc golf or just disc golf alongside some other beginners and make friends? This next Tuesday (the 19th, a week and some change from now) at 6:30 PM we will be holding our first beginner's disc golf game, with help from …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Have you ever wanted to learn how to disc golf or just disc golf alongside some other beginners and make friends? This next Tuesday (the 19th, a week and some change from now) at 6:30 PM we will be holding our first beginner's disc golf game, with help from members of the local disc golf community. At this event, you will not only be able to learn how to play alongside other beginners but will also be able to receive valuable tips from some more veteran disc golf players.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/mineral_springs/disc/course.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Course Map" src="/images/mineral_springs/disc/course.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This event will be held at Mineral Springs park, located on the north end of Licton Springs. This course takes the honor of being the original and only Disc Golf course in Seattle proper. Being a city course it also has a more compact intricate design making it uniquely well suited to learning disc golf technique.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/mineral_springs/disc/steps.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Steps" src="/images/mineral_springs/disc/steps.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/mineral_springs/disc/hole_4.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Hole 4 Map" src="/images/mineral_springs/disc/hole_4.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/mineral_springs/disc/hole_4_close.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Hole 4" src="/images/mineral_springs/disc/hole_4_close.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/mineral_springs/disc/hole_6.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Hole 6" src="/images/mineral_springs/disc/hole_6.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having never Disc Golfed ourselves, my wife and I went by the course this morning to get some sense of the game. In the course, we were struck by not only the beauty and tranquillity of a course nestled in the city but also by the friendliness of disc golfers. We ran into Mary and Tony who took us through both some of the basics of Disc Golf and the unique traits of this course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/mineral_springs/disc/mary_and_tony.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Mary and Tony" src="/images/mineral_springs/disc/mary_and_tony.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are poles throughout the course used to hold up netting that separates pathways and different sections of the course.
They told us that every time your disc hits one of those poles and makes a little ringing sound, it's called North Park Love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/mineral_springs/disc/poles.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="North park love" src="/images/mineral_springs/disc/poles.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hope to enjoy the summer weather, learn how to Disc Golf, and ring in some North Park Love with some of you there!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Event Details&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration: line-through;"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Facebook Event&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/180160409336598/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/180160409336598/&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Event start time&lt;/strong&gt;: Tuesday 6/19/2018 6:30 PM &lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;UPDATE&lt;/strong&gt; We've made this a recurring event, the third Tuesday of every month. The next scheduled beginners game is: &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Facebook Event&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/618053928556827/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/618053928556827/&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Event start time&lt;/strong&gt;: Tuesday 7/17/2018 6:30 PM  &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Location&lt;/strong&gt;:
1500 N 105th St, Seattle, WA 98133 &lt;br /&gt;
Meet at the benches by the south entrance to the park
&lt;a href="/images/mineral_springs/disc/south_entrance.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Meetup Point" src="/images/mineral_springs/disc/south_entrance.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="General"></category><category term="Activities"></category><category term="Fun"></category><category term="Disc Golf"></category></entry><entry><title>Opinion: The time is now to keep momentum going and rezone Aurora</title><link href="https://lovelicton.com/the-time-to-rezone-aurora-is-now.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-06-04T01:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-06-04T01:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>timothycrosley</name></author><id>tag:lovelicton.com,2018-06-04:/the-time-to-rezone-aurora-is-now.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;As part of the upcoming HALA legislation we have the unprecedented opportunity to reshape Aurora Avenue into the hub of a vibrant walkable community. Regardless what your thoughts are on the overall legislation, I encourage you to let our council members know what we as a community want from Aurora …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As part of the upcoming HALA legislation we have the unprecedented opportunity to reshape Aurora Avenue into the hub of a vibrant walkable community. Regardless what your thoughts are on the overall legislation, I encourage you to let our council members know what we as a community want from Aurora. For me that means more gems like the wonderful neighborhood shops that fill Oak Tree Plaza and fewer storage facilities. Either way, as the final public hearing happens tomorrow (June 5th) this may be your last opportunity to let the council know how you feel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;From our friends at &lt;a href="http://auroralictonuv.org/"&gt;ALUV&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dear ALUV Friends and Neighbors,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you for continued interest in bringing positive change to the Aurora Ave Corridor, specifically from N. 84th to N. 110th. As we continue our efforts to increase public safety via “eyes on the street” our biggest obstacle is the commercial zoning designation. This zoning has recently allowed for two public storage facilities to be built that provide no housing or walkable amenities to our Residential Urban Village as designated by the city in 1999.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please email your support for the proposed zoning changes from Commercial (C) to Neighborhood Commercial (NC) to the Seattle City Council &lt;a href="mailto: council@seattle.gov"&gt;council@seattle.gov&lt;/a&gt; prior to JUNE 5th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-&amp;gt; &lt;a href="http://auroralictonuv.org/2018/05/31/call-to-action-support-aurora-ave-rezoning/"&gt;Click here for the email template from ALUV&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="General"></category><category term="Zoning"></category><category term="Pedestrian"></category><category term="Business"></category></entry><entry><title>Aurora is getting cleaned up.</title><link href="https://lovelicton.com/aurora-is-getting-cleaned-up.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-05-30T01:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-05-30T01:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>timothycrosley</name></author><id>tag:lovelicton.com,2018-05-30:/aurora-is-getting-cleaned-up.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The next time you walk or ride up Aurora you may notice it's cleaner than usual. In more ways than one, positive changes are starting to take hold on this historical Seattle Avenue. The city's proactive litter abatement pilot program &lt;a href="http://komonews.com/news/local/pro-active-litter-teams-patrolling-six-seattle-neighborhoods"&gt;has added Licton Spring's stretch of Aurora&lt;/a&gt; to its 2x …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The next time you walk or ride up Aurora you may notice it's cleaner than usual. In more ways than one, positive changes are starting to take hold on this historical Seattle Avenue. The city's proactive litter abatement pilot program &lt;a href="http://komonews.com/news/local/pro-active-litter-teams-patrolling-six-seattle-neighborhoods"&gt;has added Licton Spring's stretch of Aurora&lt;/a&gt; to its 2x weekly cleanup. This brave crew cleans up everything from coffee cups to used syringes, hopefully helping to encourage a sustainably clean street over time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the same time, SPD and Licton Spring's own North Precinct have been hard at work to bust a local pawn shop that incentivised theft within North Seattle. Along with the closure of the business, this had the side effect of finally permanently removing an Aurora fixture that we will all be happy to see go:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/aurora/rare_coins.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Aurora Lady Statue" src="/images/aurora/rare_coins.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(See more on the &lt;a href="http://spdblotter.seattle.gov/2018/05/21/north-seattle-coin-shop-busted-for-selling-stolen-goods/"&gt;spdblotter&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, &lt;a href="http://www.wsdot.wa.gov/Projects/SR99/RoySt145thPaving/default.htm"&gt;Aurora is going to be repaved and sidewalk ramps made ADA compliant over the next year&lt;/a&gt;. Which, while sure to be an inconvenience during construction and &lt;a href="http://kuow.org/post/state-repaving-aurora-thats-chance-build-sidewalks-no"&gt;lacking the sidewalk improvements Aurora desperately needs&lt;/a&gt;, will hopefully be worth it upon completion as it plays a part in increasing road safety and accessibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While more work is needed along this historic stretch of Seattle, it's encouraging that we are starting to see progress toward an Aurora that we can all take pride in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/aurora/historic.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Historic 99" src="/images/aurora/historic.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="General"></category><category term="Improvements"></category><category term="Transit"></category></entry><entry><title>Local Licton Pet Highlight - A Famous Licton Springs Resident</title><link href="https://lovelicton.com/henri_le_chat_noir.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-05-21T23:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-05-21T23:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>timothycrosley</name></author><id>tag:lovelicton.com,2018-05-21:/henri_le_chat_noir.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;An anonymous reader of LoveLicton let us know about a celebrity living right here in Licton Springs:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The “tuxedo” cat, Henry, known by his stage name, Henri, Le Chat Noir, is a resident of our
neighborhood, though he lives in quiet obscurity, not troubled by his You-Tube fame. He plays …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;An anonymous reader of LoveLicton let us know about a celebrity living right here in Licton Springs:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The “tuxedo” cat, Henry, known by his stage name, Henri, Le Chat Noir, is a resident of our
neighborhood, though he lives in quiet obscurity, not troubled by his You-Tube fame. He plays the role
of a depressed, French cat in a series of videos that have garnered millions of viewers. Henry has over
170,000 Facebook followers and has been featured on Animal Planet and in People magazine. Henry also
has two books out on his philosophy and a Wikipedia page. But no French Riviera for this feline! “I love
Licton”, says Henry, “it’s the best place in the world for a spoiled, handsome cat.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/pets/cats/henri/feed_me.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Henri Waits for Food" src="/images/pets/cats/henri/feed_me.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/wx5Of3X-VJw" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; encrypted-media" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Want to see more Henri, Le Chat Noir?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCKV9BaMeTZ1XkpTzvJl226Q"&gt;Henri on YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://tinyurl.com/henrifb"&gt;Henri on Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://twitter.com//HenriLeChatNoir"&gt;Henri on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Have your own uniquely awesome pet or something you want to share with your neighbors?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us know! We would love to feature your pet or story on our blog. Add a comment on this blog post or &lt;a href="/pages/connect-with-us.html"&gt;contact us directly&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Pets"></category><category term="Cats"></category><category term="Local Highlight"></category><category term="Local Celebrity"></category></entry><entry><title>Outlines Provide Sneak Peak of Street Improvements</title><link href="https://lovelicton.com/street_improvements_preview_2018.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-05-14T23:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-05-14T23:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>timothycrosley</name></author><id>tag:lovelicton.com,2018-05-14:/street_improvements_preview_2018.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A friend of the blog dropped a hint letting us know that a new traffic circle has been outlined for N 97th and Wallingford Ave N, which SDOT plans on having completed this summer! The circle will be a very welcome addition to the area, as, despite lots of warning …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A friend of the blog dropped a hint letting us know that a new traffic circle has been outlined for N 97th and Wallingford Ave N, which SDOT plans on having completed this summer! The circle will be a very welcome addition to the area, as, despite lots of warning signs and kids, sees more than its fair share of speeding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/street_improvements/signs.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Warning Signs" src="/images/street_improvements/signs.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/street_improvements/97th.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Slow Down Man" src="/images/street_improvements/97th.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/street_improvements/circle.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Location of new Circle" src="/images/street_improvements/circle.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This new circle will complement the existing one at N 95th, hopefully reducing speed driving up Wallingford.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/street_improvements/circle.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="95th Circle" src="/images/street_improvements/95th.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On my walk up to N 97th, I also noticed initials outlines for a continuation of the N 92nd bike path by the new School.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/street_improvements/92nd_east.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="92nd Bike Path Looking East" src="/images/street_improvements/92nd_east.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/street_improvements/92nd_west.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="92nd Bike Path Looking West" src="/images/street_improvements/92nd_west.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find out about some more street improvements scheduled to be completed this year on &lt;a href="https://www.seattle.gov/transportation/projects-and-programs/programs/greenways-program/north-seattle"&gt;SDOT's Greenway &amp;amp; School Safety Project Website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enjoy this great weather! And hopefully, as the season progresses, we will all be able to enjoy some safer streets!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="General"></category><category term="Improvements"></category><category term="Transit"></category><category term="School"></category></entry><entry><title>Big Tesla: where nature and technology meet</title><link href="https://lovelicton.com/tesla_head_2018.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-05-02T23:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-05-02T23:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>timothycrosley</name></author><id>tag:lovelicton.com,2018-05-02:/tesla_head_2018.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Right to the northwest of Licton Springs park at the Seattle City Light North Service Center lies a beautiful art piece by Merrily Tompkins.
The art not only serves as a sign of nicer weather, as flowers bloom from Tesla's head but also serves as a great reminder that technology …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Right to the northwest of Licton Springs park at the Seattle City Light North Service Center lies a beautiful art piece by Merrily Tompkins.
The art not only serves as a sign of nicer weather, as flowers bloom from Tesla's head but also serves as a great reminder that technology and
nature can coexist in harmony. In a way, it's the perfect Seattle art piece, a city nestled in some of the most profoundly beautiful natural
environments while leading the way in our technological future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/tesla/up_close.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Close Up" src="/images/tesla/up_close.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/tesla/sign.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Close Up" src="/images/tesla/sign.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information about this work:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.publicartarchive.org/work/big-tesla"&gt;Public Art Archive&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.seattlestar.net/2014/03/celebrating-seattle-big-tesla/"&gt;Celebrating Seattle: Big Tesla&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next time you walk from Licton Springs Park to the Oak Tree Plaza, take some time to enjoy this unique and creative piece of art.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="General"></category><category term="Outdoors"></category><category term="Art"></category></entry><entry><title>Mineral Springs Park Community Meeting</title><link href="https://lovelicton.com/mineral-springs-meeting-may-1.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-04-22T11:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-04-22T11:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>timothycrosley</name></author><id>tag:lovelicton.com,2018-04-22:/mineral-springs-meeting-may-1.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UPDATE: The meeting was originally set to start at 7 PM but was then changed to a 6 PM start time by Seattle Parks and Recreation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Join other members of the community on May 1st, 6:00PM-8:30PM, to help shape the future of Mineral Springs park!
The meeting will …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UPDATE: The meeting was originally set to start at 7 PM but was then changed to a 6 PM start time by Seattle Parks and Recreation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Join other members of the community on May 1st, 6:00PM-8:30PM, to help shape the future of Mineral Springs park!
The meeting will be open to the general public, so whether you live near the park or frequent it for disk golf, this is an
important meeting to attend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/mineral_springs/bench.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Mineral Springs Park" src="/images/mineral_springs/bench.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The meeting will be held at Meridian Health Clinic, room 110, 10521 Meridian Ave N, Seattle, which is right next to the park:
&lt;a href="/images/mineral_springs/clinic.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Meridian Health Clinic" src="/images/mineral_springs/clinic.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hope to see you there!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/620773244941071/"&gt;Facebook Event&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/mineral_springs/2018_may_meeting.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="2018 May Meeting" src="/images/mineral_springs/2018_may_meeting.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="General"></category><category term="Community Meeting"></category><category term="Event"></category><category term="Outdoors"></category><category term="Parks"></category></entry><entry><title>El Patio replaces Tropicos Breeze</title><link href="https://lovelicton.com/tropicos-breeze-is-gone.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-04-19T20:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-04-19T20:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>timothycrosley</name></author><id>tag:lovelicton.com,2018-04-19:/tropicos-breeze-is-gone.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Serving up delicious Latin Cuisine right on Aurora Avenue, Tropicos Breeze has long been one of Licton Spring's most beloved restaurants. So, when I was told the Licton Springs location had closed, I feared the worse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/tropicos/patio.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="El Patio Entrance" src="/images/tropicos/patio.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rushing to the restaurant after work, I was greeted not by Tropicos Breeze, but …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Serving up delicious Latin Cuisine right on Aurora Avenue, Tropicos Breeze has long been one of Licton Spring's most beloved restaurants. So, when I was told the Licton Springs location had closed, I feared the worse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/tropicos/patio.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="El Patio Entrance" src="/images/tropicos/patio.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rushing to the restaurant after work, I was greeted not by Tropicos Breeze, but by El Patio. What a quick transformation! Entering El Patio, I saw familiar faces and after talking to the staff learned what had taken place. The Licton Spring's Tropicos Breeze location was sold to the owner's cousin. The new restaurant, I was told, retains the same staff and great quality food we have come to love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/tropicos/patio_2.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="El Patio Patio" src="/images/tropicos/patio_2.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I ordered Pollo en Crema and Horchata - two of my favorite standbys from the old Tropicos Breeze. You know, just to make sure I was told the truth...
And I can happily confirm: the food here is as tasty as ever!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/tropicos/food.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="El Patio Patio" src="/images/tropicos/food.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/tropicos/menu.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="El Patio Patio" src="/images/tropicos/menu.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether you're a long time fan of the old Tropicos Breeze or just looking for some good Latin Cuisine, I encourage you to welcome El Patio to the neighborhood!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="General"></category><category term="Restaurants"></category><category term="Patio"></category><category term="Business"></category></entry><entry><title>Licton Spring's P-Patch: Bringing Community Together</title><link href="https://lovelicton.com/licton-springs-ppatch-2018.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-04-11T08:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-04-11T08:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>amandacrosley</name></author><id>tag:lovelicton.com,2018-04-11:/licton-springs-ppatch-2018.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;It's officially spring time and with the warmer weather brings sunshine and blooming flowers. Did you know that Licton Springs has a &lt;a href="http://www.seattle.gov/neighborhoods/programs-and-services/p-patch-community-gardening/p-patch-list/licton-springs"&gt;community p-patch&lt;/a&gt; at College Way &amp;amp; North 92nd St?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;What is a P-Patch?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;P-Patch is the name given to community gardens that are managed by the Seattle P-Patch Community …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It's officially spring time and with the warmer weather brings sunshine and blooming flowers. Did you know that Licton Springs has a &lt;a href="http://www.seattle.gov/neighborhoods/programs-and-services/p-patch-community-gardening/p-patch-list/licton-springs"&gt;community p-patch&lt;/a&gt; at College Way &amp;amp; North 92nd St?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;What is a P-Patch?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;P-Patch is the name given to community gardens that are managed by the Seattle P-Patch Community Gardening Program. The P-Patch program oversees 88 P-Patches over 32 acres throughout the city. Though a P-Patch, neighbors can come together to plan, plant, and grow community. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;What is the history of Licton Spring's P-Patch?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Licton Springs P-Patch dates back to 1976 as a student-driven initiative at North Seattle College. While the original community garden ended up as a school parking lot, in 2013 the North Seattle College Sustainability Committee revived the initiative. After over a year of hard work from the community digging up land, building plots, and adding compost, a community garden of 67 plots and 15,000 sq ft was developed in Licton Springs! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;How can I get involved?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For information about volunteering, events, and general p-patch activities, email &lt;a href="mailto:lictonspringsppatch@gmail.com"&gt;lictonspringsppatch@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt; or visit the community website at &lt;a href="http://www.lictonspringsppatch.wixsite.com/seattle"&gt;www.lictonspringsppatch.wixsite.com/seattle&lt;/a&gt;. The next community work party will be on Sunday, 4/15 from 11am to 1pm at the garden. The next leadership meeting will be on the first Wednesday of May (5/2) at 6pm at the OCEE building room 229 on North Seattle College campus. &lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="General"></category><category term="Outdoors"></category><category term="Parks"></category><category term="Gardening"></category></entry><entry><title>Want to be involved in the Licton Springs Community?</title><link href="https://lovelicton.com/new-community-calendar-and-resource.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-04-08T16:57:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-04-08T16:57:00-07:00</updated><author><name>timothycrosley</name></author><id>tag:lovelicton.com,2018-04-08:/new-community-calendar-and-resource.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Want to stay up to date on all the community events and meetings going on in Licton Springs and surrounding areas? There are now a few more ways to do just that:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Check out the &lt;a href="https://lovelicton.com/pages/community-calendar.html"&gt;Licton Springs Community Calendar&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Discover all the &lt;a href="https://lovelicton.com/pages/get-involved.html"&gt;Ways to Get Involved&lt;/a&gt; including the community groups …&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Want to stay up to date on all the community events and meetings going on in Licton Springs and surrounding areas? There are now a few more ways to do just that:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Check out the &lt;a href="https://lovelicton.com/pages/community-calendar.html"&gt;Licton Springs Community Calendar&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Discover all the &lt;a href="https://lovelicton.com/pages/get-involved.html"&gt;Ways to Get Involved&lt;/a&gt; including the community groups available to join.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finally, if you want to &lt;a href="https://lovelicton.com/pages/connect-with-us.html"&gt;stay connected&lt;/a&gt; to LoveLicton there are many ways including a dedicated &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/groups/lovelicton/"&gt;Facebook Group&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/lictonsprings/"&gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="/feeds/all.rss.xml"&gt;RSS Feed&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don't see your event or community group listed? Contact us at: &lt;a href="mailto:lovelicton@gmail.com"&gt;lovelicton@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See you around the neighborhood!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="General"></category><category term="Website"></category><category term="Features"></category></entry><entry><title>This small Seattle neighborhood is experiencing big changes.</title><link href="https://lovelicton.com/more-improvements-coming.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-04-05T01:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-04-05T01:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>timothycrosley</name></author><id>tag:lovelicton.com,2018-04-05:/more-improvements-coming.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Licton Springs is looking to become even more well prepared for the urban demands of being a &amp;lt; 14 minute light rail ride from downtown. It already has relatively high side-walk coverage and population density for the North Seattle area. It is also full of pro-growth and housing community groups - with …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Licton Springs is looking to become even more well prepared for the urban demands of being a &amp;lt; 14 minute light rail ride from downtown. It already has relatively high side-walk coverage and population density for the North Seattle area. It is also full of pro-growth and housing community groups - with no noticeable Nimby presence. And, with the light rail approaching in a few more years, it appears the community will be well positioned to take on the growth it desires. The neighbourhood has been seeing additional improvements planned and completed at an unprecedented pace. It's hard just to keep track of all the projects going on! To try and make it a bit easier: I've gone ahead and taken inventory of all the projects I'm aware of and mapped them out by location, start time, and end time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/improvements.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Sign" src="/images/improvements.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Did I miss anything? If so, please let me know in a comment below.
In any case, we certainly have an exciting few years to look forward to! &lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="General"></category><category term="Improvements"></category><category term="Transit"></category><category term="School"></category></entry><entry><title>Hidden in urban Seattle a nearly 100 year old duck oasis lives on</title><link href="https://lovelicton.com/pillings-pond.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-03-25T01:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-03-25T01:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>timothycrosley</name></author><id>tag:lovelicton.com,2018-03-25:/pillings-pond.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;As the weather gets nicer - if you find yourself wanting to see some ducks you may think the best place to do so would be Green Lake or one of Seattle's many parks. However, the best place to catch a glimpse of the local duck population in Seattle is right …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As the weather gets nicer - if you find yourself wanting to see some ducks you may think the best place to do so would be Green Lake or one of Seattle's many parks. However, the best place to catch a glimpse of the local duck population in Seattle is right here in Licton Springs. Located on N 90th St between Densmore and Ashworth Ave N and near the new school: Pilling's Pond remains as a reminder of Chuck Pilling's legacy. This is the spot where he became the first successful breeder of the hooded merganser, bufflehead and harlequin ducks. Here you can still find hundreds of ducks enjoying the pond. While there has been some concern about the future of the pond due to a sale, the new owners have expressed their desire to keep the legacy going and have allowed Dave Kunkle to continue the maintenance of this great North Seattle landmark.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NOTE: You can't enter the pond but can safely view the ducks from behind the wired fence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/pond/sign.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Sign" src="/images/pond/sign.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/pond/2.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Ducks 2" src="/images/pond/2.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/pond/3.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Ducks 3" src="/images/pond/3.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/pond/4.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Ducks 4" src="/images/pond/4.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/pond/5.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Ducks 5" src="/images/pond/5.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/pond/6.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Ducks 6" src="/images/pond/6.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/pond/7.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Ducks 7" src="/images/pond/7.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/pond/8.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Ducks 8" src="/images/pond/8.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/pond/9.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Ducks 9" src="/images/pond/9.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/pond/10.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Ducks 10" src="/images/pond/10.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/pond/11.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Ducks 11" src="/images/pond/11.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, as you enjoy this warmer weather, take some time to appreciate Pilling's Pond, its many duck inhabitants, and the legacy of Chuck Pilling. &lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="General"></category><category term="Outdoors"></category></entry><entry><title>Pedestrian Bridge Updates</title><link href="https://lovelicton.com/pedestrian-bridge-meeting-updates.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-03-22T01:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-03-22T01:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>timothycrosley</name></author><id>tag:lovelicton.com,2018-03-22:/pedestrian-bridge-meeting-updates.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I was able to make it to yesterday's meeting at Neighborcare Health to discuss the development of the new pedestrian bridge and wanted to share my main takeaways:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The college has expressed approval with the new design alleviating concerns that disagreements would lead to no bridge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new design decreases …&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I was able to make it to yesterday's meeting at Neighborcare Health to discuss the development of the new pedestrian bridge and wanted to share my main takeaways:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The college has expressed approval with the new design alleviating concerns that disagreements would lead to no bridge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new design decreases costs and the maximum slope while improving visibility and addressing the concerns of North Seattle College.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project has secured all necessary funding contingent on it being complete before the light rail opens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It will take 10-15 minutes to walk from the base of the bridge to the entrance of the transit center.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bridge will incorporate scenic overlooks and art installation(s).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no bike/pedestrian or direction lane separation planned for the bridge. Instead, users will be expected to utilize the generously wide (16ft) path to follow standard right of way rules. Additionally, visual and tactile cues will be added near mixing areas, transition zones, and overlooks providing helpful cues to bicyclists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;VIA Architecture expressed pride in their work to create an affordable design that will still be an enjoyable experience to walk over, highlight the beauty inherit on both sides of I5, and act as another North Seattle landmark.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Talking with Eric from VIA Architecture, I learned that they use VR to verify what a realistic experience of their designs will be once built.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also learned about a ton of other exciting things planned for Licton Springs and the surrounding area that will be rolling out over the next few years. Expect a follow-up post with a full overview of all these changes and when we can expect them.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="General"></category><category term="Transportation"></category><category term="Pedestrian"></category></entry><entry><title>A new bridge is set to bring two Seattle neighbourhoods closer together</title><link href="https://lovelicton.com/pedestrian-bridge-updates.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-03-14T07:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-03-14T07:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>timothycrosley</name></author><id>tag:lovelicton.com,2018-03-14:/pedestrian-bridge-updates.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Licton Springs is set to feel even more connected to Maple Leaf and the rest of the Northgate area. With the construction of a pedestrian bridge on 100th, you will never have to walk more than 5 minutes North or South to cross over I5 and into Maple Leaf. This …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Licton Springs is set to feel even more connected to Maple Leaf and the rest of the Northgate area. With the construction of a pedestrian bridge on 100th, you will never have to walk more than 5 minutes North or South to cross over I5 and into Maple Leaf. This bridge is set to complement the existing Northgate Way underpass, 92nd overpass, and nearby 80th overpass directly connecting Licton Springs to the Northgate Transit Station and upcoming light rail:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/bridge/i5_routes.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Existing routes over I5" src="/images/bridge/i5_routes.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bridge is proposed to be built at the north end of North Seattle College, giving it a straight path over to the transit center:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/bridge/100th.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Proposed location" src="/images/bridge/100th.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/bridge/100th_up_close.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Proposed location" src="/images/bridge/100th_up_close.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To find out more about the plans for the new pedestrian bridge you can read &lt;a href="http://www.seattle.gov/transportation/projects-and-programs/programs/bridges-stairs-and-other-structures/bridges/northgate-pedestrian-and-bicycle-bridge"&gt;Seattle's official overview of the project&lt;/a&gt;.
There are also 3 upcoming opportunities to give feedback on the project before construction begins:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/443591789391586/"&gt;Mon. 3.19.18, 12-1:30 PM | North Seattle College, The Grove&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/205339450220405/"&gt;Tues. 3.20.18, 8-9:30 AM | Aljoya Thornton Place&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wed. 3.21.18, 5-6:30 PM | Neighborcare Health at Meridian&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In related news, at the same time as the bridge will be under construction, it seems likely an improved Northgate Mall will also be underway to welcome us upon completion:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.seattletimes.com/business/real-estate/northgate-mall-readies-huge-overhaul-with-office-and-housing-elements-as-north-seattle-neighborhood-transforms/"&gt;Northgate Mall plans huge overhaul with housing, offices as North Seattle transforms&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It appears exciting times are ahead for Licton Springs and North Seattle!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="General"></category><category term="Transportation"></category><category term="Pedestrian"></category></entry><entry><title>An early preview of Spring in Licton Springs</title><link href="https://lovelicton.com/an-early-preview-of-spring-in-licton-springs.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-03-12T01:18:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-03-12T01:18:00-07:00</updated><author><name>timothycrosley</name></author><id>tag:lovelicton.com,2018-03-12:/an-early-preview-of-spring-in-licton-springs.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/spring/entrance.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Park Entrance" src="/images/spring/entrance.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In hopefully an early preview of what Spring has to offer this year, Licton Springs Park was a beautiful sight this weekend backdropped by clear
Seattle skies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/spring/play_area.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Play Area" src="/images/spring/play_area.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/spring/trees.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Trees!" src="/images/spring/trees.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/spring/trail.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Trail" src="/images/spring/trail.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/spring/creek.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Creek" src="/images/spring/creek.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/spring/hill.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Hill" src="/images/spring/hill.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/spring/frisbee.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Frisbee" src="/images/spring/frisbee.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/spring/bridge.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Bridge" src="/images/spring/bridge.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/spring/bird.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Bird" src="/images/spring/bird.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/spring/reaching.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Trees Reaching for the Sky" src="/images/spring/reaching.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/spring/sign.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Sign" src="/images/spring/sign.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/spring/entrance.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Park Entrance" src="/images/spring/entrance.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In hopefully an early preview of what Spring has to offer this year, Licton Springs Park was a beautiful sight this weekend backdropped by clear
Seattle skies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/spring/play_area.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Play Area" src="/images/spring/play_area.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/spring/trees.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Trees!" src="/images/spring/trees.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/spring/trail.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Trail" src="/images/spring/trail.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/spring/creek.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Creek" src="/images/spring/creek.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/spring/hill.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Hill" src="/images/spring/hill.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/spring/frisbee.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Frisbee" src="/images/spring/frisbee.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/spring/bridge.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Bridge" src="/images/spring/bridge.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/spring/bird.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Bird" src="/images/spring/bird.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/spring/reaching.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Trees Reaching for the Sky" src="/images/spring/reaching.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/spring/sign.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Sign" src="/images/spring/sign.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="General"></category><category term="Outdoors"></category></entry></feed>