<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Love Licton - Aurora</title><link href="https://lovelicton.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://lovelicton.com/feeds/aurora.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://lovelicton.com/</id><updated>2018-09-26T20:00:00-07:00</updated><entry><title>Licton Springs Tiny House Village will close permanently March 2019</title><link href="https://lovelicton.com/licton-springs-tiny-house-village-to-close.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-09-26T20:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-09-26T20:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>timothycrosley</name></author><id>tag:lovelicton.com,2018-09-26:/licton-springs-tiny-house-village-to-close.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;We learned today that the controversial Aurora Ave. tiny house village within Licton Springs will be closing for good March of next year. While many members of the local community have voiced their support for helping the least fortunate among us and have diligently donated food to the village, there …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We learned today that the controversial Aurora Ave. tiny house village within Licton Springs will be closing for good March of next year. While many members of the local community have voiced their support for helping the least fortunate among us and have diligently donated food to the village, there has been disagreement that the village as designed is the best route to solve the problem. Since its creation there have been many complaints of crime that have been attributed to the village as well as a general concern around having an official policy of allowing illicit drug use just blocks from 3 schools, 2 of which are for elementary aged children.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the &lt;a href="https://homelessness.seattle.gov/tiny-house-village-update-next-steps-for-licton-springs/"&gt;city's homeless response blog&lt;/a&gt;, they identify finding permanent houses for the remaining residents as the top priority of the site ahead of its closure, with additional case management and partner agencies brought in to expedite the process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Perspectives from around the web on the closure:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.seattletimes.com/seattle-news/homeless/controversial-tiny-house-village-for-homelessness-in-north-seattle-to-close/"&gt;SeattleTimes: Controversial tiny house village for homelessness in North Seattle to close&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.kuow.org/stories/tiny-house-village-on-aurora-set-to-close"&gt;KUOW: Tiny house village on Aurora Ave set to close&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.kiro7.com/news/local/seattle-to-close-controversial-tiny-house-encampment/841945703"&gt;KIRO: Seattle to close controversial tiny house encampment&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.king5.com/article/news/local/homeless/controversial-tiny-house-village-for-seattle-homeless-to-close/281-598435383"&gt;King 5: Controversial tiny house village for Seattle homeless to close&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.thestranger.com/slog/2018/09/26/32946409/slog-pm-aurora-avenue-tiny-house-village-slated-for-closure-bomb-threat-in-olympia-this-kayaker-got-bitch-slapped-by-nature"&gt;The Stranger/SLOG: NIMBYs get their way, tiny house village closes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><category term="General"></category><category term="Homeless"></category></entry><entry><title>City Council Unanimously Passes Aurora Licton Urban Village Moratorium Extension</title><link href="https://lovelicton.com/aurora-zone-controls-extension-2018-approval.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-09-24T20:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-09-24T20:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>timothycrosley</name></author><id>tag:lovelicton.com,2018-09-24:/aurora-zone-controls-extension-2018-approval.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today after extensive community feedback (at least 100 proponents of the moratorium and five against it) Seattle City Council unanimously passed a 6-month extension of its moratorium for new non-pedestrian-oriented developments within the Aurora Licton Urban Village:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/nUVB4JXMIHE?rel=0&amp;amp;start=6805&amp;amp;end=7149" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; encrypted-media" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The extension represents a victory for the &lt;a href="http://auroralictonuv.org/"&gt;ALUV group&lt;/a&gt; and associated members of …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today after extensive community feedback (at least 100 proponents of the moratorium and five against it) Seattle City Council unanimously passed a 6-month extension of its moratorium for new non-pedestrian-oriented developments within the Aurora Licton Urban Village:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/nUVB4JXMIHE?rel=0&amp;amp;start=6805&amp;amp;end=7149" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; encrypted-media" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The extension represents a victory for the &lt;a href="http://auroralictonuv.org/"&gt;ALUV group&lt;/a&gt; and associated members of the community who want to see Aurora transform into the center of a pedestrian friendly neighborhood that does its part to help soften our ongoing housing crises.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="General"></category><category term="Zoning"></category><category term="Pedestrian"></category><category term="Business"></category></entry><entry><title>Aurora Licton Urban Village Moratorium Extension Passes First Hurdle</title><link href="https://lovelicton.com/aurora-zone-controls-extension-2018-update.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-09-19T20:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-09-19T20:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>timothycrosley</name></author><id>tag:lovelicton.com,2018-09-19:/aurora-zone-controls-extension-2018-update.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today Seattle's Planning, Land Use, and Zoning Committee adopted a 6 Month extension on its moratorium for new non-pedestrian-oriented developments within the Aurora Licton Urban Village:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/lTLxqxo6q_Y?rel=0&amp;amp;start=2520&amp;amp;end=3223" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; encrypted-media" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This leaves the final fate of the extension to Seattle City Council with a vote coming up this following Monday (the 24th of September …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today Seattle's Planning, Land Use, and Zoning Committee adopted a 6 Month extension on its moratorium for new non-pedestrian-oriented developments within the Aurora Licton Urban Village:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/lTLxqxo6q_Y?rel=0&amp;amp;start=2520&amp;amp;end=3223" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; encrypted-media" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This leaves the final fate of the extension to Seattle City Council with a vote coming up this following Monday (the 24th of September).
If you have thoughts on the extension and have not yet made them heard, this represents your final opportunity, and I encourage you to follow the steps &lt;a href="http://auroralictonuv.org/2018/08/28/interim-controls-extension/"&gt;ALUV has outlined&lt;/a&gt; to contact your representatives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The committee's adoption of the ordinance followed significant feedback from our local community during their September 5 meeting:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/6rza2LUi6xY?rel=0&amp;amp;start=870&amp;amp;end=2040" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; encrypted-media" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, the first new proposed residential apartment project in some time within our Urban Village is actively &lt;a href="https://designreview.info/"&gt;gathering feedback&lt;/a&gt; up till the 26th of this month.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="General"></category><category term="Zoning"></category><category term="Pedestrian"></category><category term="Business"></category></entry><entry><title>Opinion: We need your help to extend the push for Aurora revitalization</title><link href="https://lovelicton.com/aurora-zone-controls-extension-2018.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-08-31T20:25:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-08-31T20:25:00-07:00</updated><author><name>timothycrosley</name></author><id>tag:lovelicton.com,2018-08-31:/aurora-zone-controls-extension-2018.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Call to Action:&lt;/strong&gt; We hope you will &lt;a href="http://auroralictonuv.org/2018/08/28/interim-controls-extension/"&gt;work with ALUV to extend the Aurora zoning controls&lt;/a&gt; and help ensure a vibrant Aurora Village has a chance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, I recently had to &lt;a href="https://lovelicton.com/original_north_seattle_starbucks_closing.html"&gt;report on the upcoming closure of the Oak Tree Starbucks&lt;/a&gt;, the only Coffee Shop within the Aurora Licton Urban …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Call to Action:&lt;/strong&gt; We hope you will &lt;a href="http://auroralictonuv.org/2018/08/28/interim-controls-extension/"&gt;work with ALUV to extend the Aurora zoning controls&lt;/a&gt; and help ensure a vibrant Aurora Village has a chance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, I recently had to &lt;a href="https://lovelicton.com/original_north_seattle_starbucks_closing.html"&gt;report on the upcoming closure of the Oak Tree Starbucks&lt;/a&gt;, the only Coffee Shop within the Aurora Licton Urban Village (ALUV). This came not too long after the nearby Gold's Gym, which brought additional caffeine craving foot traffic to the area, closed to be replaced by a storage facility. This facility &lt;a href="https://lovelicton.com/golds-gym-hearing.html"&gt;did have an appeal put forth&lt;/a&gt;, but it was dropped before being heard. This is one of 2 large storage facilities being built in the area. And while some storage is undoubtedly necessary, it is sad to see so much land taken off the market. Property that could instead be used for much needed additional housing which would support a thriving retail core within ALUV. As it is, the village is set to contain at least four storage facilities and not a single coffee shop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://lovelicton.com/golds-gym-hearing.html"&gt;&lt;img alt="Gold's Gym becomes Public Storage." src="/images/golds_gym/public_storage.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only thing that has kept even more of the land along Aurora from being repurposed for storage use is a temporary moratorium that was put in place October 2017, right after these storage facilities applied for permits. When this moratorium was passed, the intention was that it would act as a stop-gap measure until permanent zoning changes took effect with the passage of HALA. Predictably though, that law has been delayed by legal challenges, leaving the moratorium set to expire soon with no zoning changes in place. On Wednesday, Sept. 5th at 9:30 AM the Seattle City Council Planning, Land Use and Zoning (PLUZ) Committee will hold a public hearing on the renewal of the Interim Zoning Controls for the Aurora Licton Residential Urban Village. We hope to encourage you to &lt;a href="http://auroralictonuv.org/2018/08/28/interim-controls-extension/"&gt;come out in support of the extension and/or email the Seattle City Council&lt;/a&gt; with your thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to make it clear: this is not an attack on the many existing businesses along Aurora that may fall into the categories being blocked by this extension. Many of them are family run, have been here for decades, and have always done their best to help the community. We are glad they are here, appreciate their contributions, and hope they continue to thrive. This zoning extension and the permanent zoning changes proposed will not affect existing businesses or already pending permits. The goal is only to encourage more housing, and pedestrian-friendly businesses are built in existing empty lots and new lots as they become available. We believe this will result in a more lively and friendly area that will benefit both residents and existing businesses alike.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Call to Action:&lt;/strong&gt; We hope you will &lt;a href="http://auroralictonuv.org/2018/08/28/interim-controls-extension/"&gt;work with ALUV to extend the Aurora zoning controls&lt;/a&gt; and help ensure a vibrant Aurora Village has a chance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;</content><category term="General"></category><category term="Zoning"></category><category term="Pedestrian"></category><category term="Business"></category></entry><entry><title>Opinion: The time is now to keep momentum going and rezone Aurora</title><link href="https://lovelicton.com/the-time-to-rezone-aurora-is-now.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-06-04T01:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-06-04T01:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>timothycrosley</name></author><id>tag:lovelicton.com,2018-06-04:/the-time-to-rezone-aurora-is-now.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;As part of the upcoming HALA legislation we have the unprecedented opportunity to reshape Aurora Avenue into the hub of a vibrant walkable community. Regardless what your thoughts are on the overall legislation, I encourage you to let our council members know what we as a community want from Aurora …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As part of the upcoming HALA legislation we have the unprecedented opportunity to reshape Aurora Avenue into the hub of a vibrant walkable community. Regardless what your thoughts are on the overall legislation, I encourage you to let our council members know what we as a community want from Aurora. For me that means more gems like the wonderful neighborhood shops that fill Oak Tree Plaza and fewer storage facilities. Either way, as the final public hearing happens tomorrow (June 5th) this may be your last opportunity to let the council know how you feel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;From our friends at &lt;a href="http://auroralictonuv.org/"&gt;ALUV&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dear ALUV Friends and Neighbors,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you for continued interest in bringing positive change to the Aurora Ave Corridor, specifically from N. 84th to N. 110th. As we continue our efforts to increase public safety via “eyes on the street” our biggest obstacle is the commercial zoning designation. This zoning has recently allowed for two public storage facilities to be built that provide no housing or walkable amenities to our Residential Urban Village as designated by the city in 1999.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please email your support for the proposed zoning changes from Commercial (C) to Neighborhood Commercial (NC) to the Seattle City Council &lt;a href="mailto: council@seattle.gov"&gt;council@seattle.gov&lt;/a&gt; prior to JUNE 5th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-&amp;gt; &lt;a href="http://auroralictonuv.org/2018/05/31/call-to-action-support-aurora-ave-rezoning/"&gt;Click here for the email template from ALUV&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="General"></category><category term="Zoning"></category><category term="Pedestrian"></category><category term="Business"></category></entry><entry><title>Aurora is getting cleaned up.</title><link href="https://lovelicton.com/aurora-is-getting-cleaned-up.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-05-30T01:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-05-30T01:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>timothycrosley</name></author><id>tag:lovelicton.com,2018-05-30:/aurora-is-getting-cleaned-up.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The next time you walk or ride up Aurora you may notice it's cleaner than usual. In more ways than one, positive changes are starting to take hold on this historical Seattle Avenue. The city's proactive litter abatement pilot program &lt;a href="http://komonews.com/news/local/pro-active-litter-teams-patrolling-six-seattle-neighborhoods"&gt;has added Licton Spring's stretch of Aurora&lt;/a&gt; to its 2x …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The next time you walk or ride up Aurora you may notice it's cleaner than usual. In more ways than one, positive changes are starting to take hold on this historical Seattle Avenue. The city's proactive litter abatement pilot program &lt;a href="http://komonews.com/news/local/pro-active-litter-teams-patrolling-six-seattle-neighborhoods"&gt;has added Licton Spring's stretch of Aurora&lt;/a&gt; to its 2x weekly cleanup. This brave crew cleans up everything from coffee cups to used syringes, hopefully helping to encourage a sustainably clean street over time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the same time, SPD and Licton Spring's own North Precinct have been hard at work to bust a local pawn shop that incentivised theft within North Seattle. Along with the closure of the business, this had the side effect of finally permanently removing an Aurora fixture that we will all be happy to see go:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/aurora/rare_coins.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Aurora Lady Statue" src="/images/aurora/rare_coins.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(See more on the &lt;a href="http://spdblotter.seattle.gov/2018/05/21/north-seattle-coin-shop-busted-for-selling-stolen-goods/"&gt;spdblotter&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, &lt;a href="http://www.wsdot.wa.gov/Projects/SR99/RoySt145thPaving/default.htm"&gt;Aurora is going to be repaved and sidewalk ramps made ADA compliant over the next year&lt;/a&gt;. Which, while sure to be an inconvenience during construction and &lt;a href="http://kuow.org/post/state-repaving-aurora-thats-chance-build-sidewalks-no"&gt;lacking the sidewalk improvements Aurora desperately needs&lt;/a&gt;, will hopefully be worth it upon completion as it plays a part in increasing road safety and accessibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While more work is needed along this historic stretch of Seattle, it's encouraging that we are starting to see progress toward an Aurora that we can all take pride in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/aurora/historic.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Historic 99" src="/images/aurora/historic.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="General"></category><category term="Improvements"></category><category term="Transit"></category></entry></feed>