<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Love Licton - Holidays</title><link href="https://lovelicton.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://lovelicton.com/feeds/holidays.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://lovelicton.com/</id><updated>2018-11-22T15:00:00-08:00</updated><subtitle>The Licton Springs Blog</subtitle><entry><title>Happy Thanksgiving!</title><link href="https://lovelicton.com/happy-thanksgiving-2018.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-11-22T15:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2018-11-22T15:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>timothycrosley</name></author><id>tag:lovelicton.com,2018-11-22:/happy-thanksgiving-2018.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/thanksgiving.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Happy Thanksgiving!" src="/images/thanksgiving.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hi Neighbors!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We at LoveLicton wanted to wish you a happy Thanksgiving!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have so much to be thankful for this year:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Our readers and community members that together make this a great place to call home.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://lictonsprings.org/"&gt;Licton Springs Community Council&lt;/a&gt; as they've continued their great work of giving a …&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/thanksgiving.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Happy Thanksgiving!" src="/images/thanksgiving.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hi Neighbors!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We at LoveLicton wanted to wish you a happy Thanksgiving!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have so much to be thankful for this year:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Our readers and community members that together make this a great place to call home.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://lictonsprings.org/"&gt;Licton Springs Community Council&lt;/a&gt; as they've continued their great work of giving a unified voice to all community members and helping to lead community events (including the phenomenal Halloween event at Licton Springs Park).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://auroralictonuv.org/"&gt;ALUV&lt;/a&gt; who has been working tirelessly to improve the Aurora Corridor. Their latest work can be seen on the Aurora Ave N. pedestrian bridge art project.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://lictonspringsppatch.wixsite.com/seattle"&gt;Licton Springs P-Patch leadership&lt;/a&gt; really making our p-patch not only beautiful but a cornerstone of the community.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://seattlegreenways.org/neighborhoods/licton-haller-greenways/"&gt;Licton-haller Greenways / Seattle Neighborhood Greenways&lt;/a&gt; working to make North Seattle and Licton Springs walkable and bikeable. They've been crucial in the creation of many Licton Springs Greenways such as the one nearing completion on N 100TH street, and have been working on &lt;a href="https://lovelicton.com/home-zone-2018.html"&gt;North Seattle's pioneering Home Zone Pilot&lt;/a&gt; right here in Licton Springs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://epiclifechurch.org/"&gt;Epic Life Church&lt;/a&gt; has consistently been there for the community. Allowing community meetings to be hosted in their church, leading a cleanup down along Aurora Ave N., and hosting community events.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://neighborcare.org/meridian"&gt;Meridian Health Center&lt;/a&gt; which has served as the closest thing to a Licton Springs Community Center. They've hosted all the Licton Springs Community Council meetings, Mineral Springs Park meetings, and even community events such as Saturday's &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/341916543226078/"&gt;board game event&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/MineralSpringsSeattle/"&gt;Friends of Mineral Springs Park&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/groups/250860298866679/"&gt;Mineral Springs Disc Golf Club&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="http://www.seattle.gov/parks"&gt;Seattle Parks and Recreation&lt;/a&gt; as they've worked to bring a strong sense of community to Seattle's only Disc Golf Park. This has lead to many events being held at the park and increased / more varied usage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.pilgrimcoffeehouse.com/"&gt;Pilgrim Coffee&lt;/a&gt; set up in Oak Tree Plaza when we &lt;a href="https://lovelicton.com/pilrim_coffee_comes_to_oaktree.html"&gt;needed them most&lt;/a&gt; and have been roasting and brewing excellent coffee for the community. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.northseattle.edu/"&gt;North Seattle College&lt;/a&gt; who've worked with the city and local community members to ensure a safe, appealing, and environmental conscience bridge is built from Licton Springs to the upcoming Northgate Lightrail Station. They've also been working with us to ensure &lt;a href="https://www.meetup.com/North-Seattle-Tech-Talks/events/255745950/"&gt;Licton Springs and North Seattle College become a hotbed of Open Source innovation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://northwestdanish.org/"&gt;Northwest Danish Association&lt;/a&gt; beyond all the great work they do for our Danish residents, they opened up their doors on many occasions for community-wide events.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/groups/131617810551046/?ref=br_rs"&gt;Buy Nothing Licton Springs&lt;/a&gt; who has done more than just provide a venue for the exchange of items, providing a forum for constructive community conversation, and the sharing of community events.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All the other countless local businesses and non-profits in Licton Springs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We hope you enjoy the holiday with your family and loved ones!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And after the holiday and Black Friday shopping is over we hope to unwind with some of you over coffee and board games:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/events/2018/november/board_games.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Board Game Event" src="/images/events/2018/november/board_games.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happy Thanksgiving!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="General"></category><category term="Community"></category><category term="Holidays"></category><category term="Celebration"></category><category term="Volunteers"></category></entry></feed>