<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Love Licton - Neighborhood</title><link href="/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="/feeds/neighborhood.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>/</id><updated>2018-07-24T20:00:00-07:00</updated><entry><title>WE'RE NUMBER 1!?</title><link href="/most-competitive-neighborhood.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-07-24T20:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-07-24T20:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>timothycrosley</name></author><id>tag:None,2018-07-24:/most-competitive-neighborhood.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Whether you call it Licton Springs, North Green Lake, North College Park, or that magical portal in-between Green Lake, Greenwood, and the Northgate mall - we are all proud to call it home. And, apparently, according to a new report from Redfin, we are not the only ones who would like …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Whether you call it Licton Springs, North Green Lake, North College Park, or that magical portal in-between Green Lake, Greenwood, and the Northgate mall - we are all proud to call it home. And, apparently, according to a new report from Redfin, we are not the only ones who would like to do so. Licton Springs showed up on &lt;a href="https://www.geekwire.com/2018/redfins-new-compete-score-ranks-markets-based-competition-homes-seattle-toughest/"&gt;Redfin's report&lt;/a&gt; as the #1 most competitive neighborhood to buy into, in not only Seattle, but the entire United States.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.geekwire.com/2018/redfins-new-compete-score-ranks-markets-based-competition-homes-seattle-toughest/"&gt;&lt;img alt="Redfin graphic" src="/images/most_competitive_neighborhood_2018.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We tied with ourselves (under the name North College Park, yep we are in the report twice) and 5 other neighborhoods including nearby Phinney Ridge for the spot. Having also received a property taxable value reassessment notice today, I'm not entirely sure it's a placement any of us were looking to achieve...&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="General"></category><category term="Neighborhood"></category><category term="Real Estate"></category></entry></feed>